片名：战略高手
山托斯银行
你有贷款申请书？好极了
- You have a loan app? - Yeah.
- Wonderful. - Terrific.
前几天我和太太吃晚饭 刚结婚
我是否能为你效劳？
How can I help you, sir?
罗莉塔
Loretta,
看到没有 哪个和经理讲话手提箱开着的人
see the man talking to your bank manager, has his case open?
那是戈登先生 助理经理之一
That's Mr. Gwendon, one of our assistant managers.
我们经理是萧恩先生但是他今天不在
Our manager is Mr. Schoen. He's not in today.
你看到那个带手提箱的人？
You see the man with the briefcase?
是
Yes.
那是我的同伙 他有枪
That's my partner. He has a gun in there.
如果你不照我说的做
If you don't do exactly what I tell you,
或者如果你想惹麻烦
or if you give me any kind of a problem at all,
我看一眼我的同伙
I'm gonna look over at my partner
他就会朝戈登先生的眉心开枪
and he's gonna shoot your Mr. Gwendon between the eyes.
好
行 去拿个大的信封
Okay, now, take one of those big envelopes
装好100 50 20钞票
and put as many 100s, 50s and 20s as you can pack into it.
不要银行的袋子
Nothing with bank straps or rubber bands.
不要橡皮筋、染色包 和有记号的钱
I don't want any dye packs. I don't want any bait money.
从第二个抽屉开始
Start with the second drawer,
然后那一个
and then the one over there underneath the money counter.
好 快 罗莉塔 钥匙就在旁边
Okay. It's okay. Come on, Loretta. Key's right there next to you.
对了
There you go.
不要最下边的
No bills off the bottom of the drawer, please.
这是你第一次被抢？
This your first time being robbed?
你做得蛮好
You're doing great.
保持笑容 不要看起来被抢的样子
Just smile, Loretta, so you don't look like you're being held up.
你笑得很美
You got a very pretty smile.
给我20元的 我要那些
Got 205? Give me the 20s. I'll take those.
不错 放到我的口袋里
Hang on. I'll put those in my pocket.
对了
There you go.
我还没有和我同伙打暗号
I haven't had to give my partner a sign, and that's good.
他会等我离开
Now he's gonna wait 30 seconds until I'm out of the building,
并确定你没按警铃
make sure you haven't set off the alarm.
如果你那么做 他就会对准戈登先生的眉心开枪
If you have, he's gonna shoot your Mr. Gwendon between the eyes. Okay?
好
Okay.
这样够了 罗莉塔
All right. I think that'll do it, Loretta.
谢谢 祝你顺利
Thank you. Have a nice day.
你也是
You too.
Hey.
她很可爱 不是吗？
She's cute, isn't she?
她看起来很甜
Yeah. She seems very nice.
那是谁？
Who was that?
要命 真要命
No, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no.
狗娘养的
Son of a bitch.
操！操！
Fuck! Fuck!
我想你加太多油了 先生 请下车
I think you flooded it. Get out of the car, sir.
你要听个笑话吗？
Hey, you wanna hear a funny story?
闭嘴！下车
Shut up and get out of the car!
好吧
Yeah. Okay.
格雷兹监狱
贝格雷兹 佛罗里达州
走 走 走！
那要干嘛？弗里
You want something, foley?
有人要逃走 想要知道何时何地吗？
Some fellas are going out of here. What if I tell you where and when?
有多少人？
How many?
我要你把风
I expect you to look out for me, let me run off work detail.
好！有多少人出去？
Okay, okay. How many going out?
听说六个 什么时候？
- I hear six. - When?
今晚
Tonight.
你知道有谁？
You know who they are?
知道 但我不能告诉你
Yes I do, but I'm not gonna tell you just yet.
上锁前在教堂见我
Meet me in the chapel just before lockdown. Okay?
你好 我爱你
I love you, baby.
今晚有大事 你兴奋吗？
Tonight's the big night. You excited?
是超级杯星期日？
Super bowl Sunday, okay?
你提前了？
So you moved it up.
你为何那么想？
Why do you think that?
今天早上我看你跑步
I saw you running this morning.
只是例行公事
Sticking to your routine, in case anybody happened to notice,
但你只跑了几里 不是平常的5里
but you only did a couple of miles, instead of your usual five.
好省点力气做大事
Saving yourself for the big event.
什么事？早做完了
What happened? You finish ahead of schedule?
你看到那里的柱子吗？
Mira, you see those posts out there?
他们要在原来的铁丝网后
They're putting up another fence
15尺的地方再筑一道
about 15 feet back the fence that's already there, you know?
如果在星期日超级杯前
So you figure, Mira, we wait till super bowl Sunday,
铁丝网已经筑好了
they have that fence built
那我们就要在挖个九到十天
then we gotta dig, what, another te... nine, ten days, baby?
是啊  我想不会
- Yeah. - I don't think so, you know?
所以今天天黑后我要逃出去
So tonight, when it's gets dark, bada-bing, I'm out of here.
你可以来 弗里
Come on, foley, you can come, all right?
谢谢提议 倒是非常诱人
I appreciate the offer, and it's tempting, but...
什么？到迈阿密要100里？
Long run to civilization, what's it a hundred miles to Miami?
我太老了 做不了这种特技
I'm too old to be trying a stunt like that, so...
你出去就寄明信片来
You send me a postcard when you get out.
迈阿密
我是阿黛尔德丽西
Adele delisi speaking.
你要接受杰克·弗里打来的由你付款的电话吗？/NOperator: Will you accept a collect call from Jack foley?
我接受
Yeah, I'll accept.
阿黛尔 你好
Hey, Adele, how you doing?
嘿 抢银行的
Hey, bank robber.
要听忠告吗？  下一次把引擎开着
Hey, want some advice? Next time, keep the engine running.
呵呵！好好笑啊
That's funny!
你要什么？杰克
So, what do you want, Jack?
阿黛尔 下星期天超级杯派对……
Adele, you know that super bowl party that was for next Sunday?
他们改变了日期 是今晚6:30
They changed the date. It's tonight at 6:30.
你说过电话不会被监听
Didn't you tell me one-time calls aren't monitored?
原则上不会
Isaid not as a rule.
对 那你为什么不直接出来
Right, so why don't you just come right out
告诉我你在说什么？
and tell me what you're talking about?
在自由国度的快嘴小姐
Listen to miss smarty mouth, out there in the free world.
自由怎么样？
Oh yeah, what's free about it?
我在找工作
I'm lookin' for work.
曼卓魔术师如何？
What about mandrake the magician?
神奇的伊米
Emile the amazing, huh?
他炒了我鱿鱼 雇了个年轻的红发的女郎
He fired me. Hired a younger girl. A redhead.
我打电话是因他们改了日期
Adele, the reason I'm calling, they changed the date.
今晚6:30
- Oh. - It is tonight, it's 6:30,
还有几小时
that's like a few hours from now.
和巴蒂联络
- Okay. - You tell buddy.
和在另一车的家伙
All right. And the guy driving the other car?
哪个？
What are you talking about?
因为你老搞不定车子
Well, seeing as you have so much luck with cars, eh?
巴蒂想要带两辆车比较稳
Buddy thought it might be better to bring two. You know?
他说找了个你在兰坡认识的家伙
He got this guy he says you know from lompoc.
葛兰什么的
Glenn somebody.
葛兰麦克
Glenn Michaels.
是他 巴蒂说葛兰认为你们这一伙真酷
Uh-huh. That's him. Yeah, buddy said Glenn thinks you guys are real cool.
阿黛尔？ 呀？
- Adele? - Yeah.
告诉巴蒂如果葛兰戴太阳眼镜
You tell buddy, I see Glenn Michaels wearing his sunglasses,
我就踩烂他
I'm gonna step on them.
我甚至一开始就不拿下来
I might not even take them off first.
好的 我会的
Okay, honey, I'll sure do that.
小心不要被射死 拜拜
Now, you try not to get shot. Bye.
夫人 我来帮你
Here, ma'am. Let me help you with these.
像你这样的漂亮女士 不应该搬杂货
Beautiful young lady like you shouldn't be carrying groceries.
该让男人来帮你做
Let a man do that for you.
我没要你帮忙 不要期望小费
Now, I didn't ask for your help, so don't expect a tip.
没问题 夫人 那我就开走你的车
Oh, that's okay, ma'am. I'll just take your car.
生日快乐
Marshall: Happy birthday.
又是一套香奈尔的套装
Did you fit another Chanel suit in here?
有更棒的 打开它
Something much better. Go ahead, open it.
天啊！真漂亮
Oh, my god. It's beautiful.
这是……
It's a...
是西格380
Sig sauer 380.
对
Right.
我真喜欢
I love it!
谢谢 爸
Thanks, dad.
生日快乐
Happy birthday.
再来些咖啡？  我不要了
- How 'bout some more coffee? - Yeah, I can't.
我要去格雷兹
I have to go out to glades, and then I'm, uh... you got something.
十点跟雷尼可见面
Meeting ray nicolet at 10:00.
哪个？ 在联邦火器局那个？
Which one is that? The a.T.F. Guy?
他现在联邦调查局 调过来了
Actually he's with the F.B.I. Now. He switched over.
但他已结婚
He's still married, though.
在法律上是 他们已分居
Technically. They're separated.
他搬出来了吗？
Oh, so he's moved out then?
差不多了
He's about to.
那他们还不算分居
Well, then they're not separated, honey.
能不能不谈这些？
Dad, can we not talk about this?
你去格雷兹干什么？
What are you doing at glades?
送传票和控诉状
Serving process a summons and complaint.
有个终身监禁的罪犯不喜欢起司通心粉
Some con doing mandatory life doesn't like macaroni and cheese.
所以他提出控诉说 他不能选择他们的服务
So, he files suit, says he doesn't have any choice on what they serve,
这侵犯了他的人权
and that violates his civil rights.
你可以到我这里
Well, you know, you can step in,
做我的调查员
work full-time for me as one of my investigators.
不 谢了
No, thanks.
你以前喜欢做
You used to like it.
爸
Dad.
你可以和那些律师、医生约会
You'd meet doctors, lawyers.
只要他们离了婚
Nothing wrong with them, necessarily, if they're divorced.
凯伦 为什么把时间那浪费在牛仔警察身上
Karen, why waste your time on some cowboy cop
他酗酒又不尊重老婆
who drinks too much and cheats on his wife?
他们就是这种人
That's how those hot shots are, all of them.
我真要走了
Hm. I really gotta go.
我们不像以前那样聊得多了
We don't talk much anymore.
我星期天过来 一起看超级杯？
How about I come over Sunday and we watch the super bowl together?
太好了
I'd like that.
爸 谢谢那支枪
Thanks for the gun, dad.
他们在你下面挖了一条地道
Right underneath you, pop. They dug a tunnel.
我没听说 地道从那里出来？
I don't hear anything. Where does the tunnel come out?
从守望塔第四根柱子
Fourth post from the guard tower.
我什么也没看见
I don't see nothing.
继续看
Just keep watching.
联邦调查局 请问找哪位？
Opera Tor: Federal Bureau of Investigation. How may I direct your call?
我是凯伦西斯柯 找雷尼可
Yeah, this is Karen sisco again for ray nicolet.
请稍等
Hold, please.
好
Yeah.
占线 你要留言吗？
The line is busy. Would you like his voice mail?
不用了 我等一下再打
Know what, forget it. Um, I'll call back later.
-好的  -谢谢
- All right. - Thanks.
还是没看到
I still don't see anything.
你马上就看到了
You will directly.
等一下
Officer: Wait a minute!
尼古丁口香糖
见鬼！
What the fuck?
铁丝网旁边有两个人！
Two men by the fence!
她在搞什么鬼？
What the hell is she doing?
别动！举起手来！
Stop! Get your hands in the air!
让他出去 他是个守卫
Get him out, he's a guard.
地道里没人
Tunnel's clear.
封锁北壁
Seal up the north face.
发生什么事？ 你说呢？
- Guard: What happened? - What the hell do you think happened,
有人越狱了
you jackass? Got a jail break!
古巴人在哪里？
The Cubans are out in the cane.
别对着我 嘿！巴蒂！
Don't point that thing at me. Hey, buddy.
别紧张 我们是好人
It's okay, we're the good guys.
你在这里干什么？
- What are you doing here? - Hey. Ho!
她只是个女孩
All right. You're just a girl.
为什么用枪？
What do you do for a living to pack a shotgun?
我是联邦警察 你被捕了！可能都是
I'm a federal marshal and you're under arrest.
我们等会再说吧
Why don't we talk about this later?
小心你的头
Watch your head.
我进来了 走吧
I'm in. Let's go!
你舒服吗？
Jack: All right. Hey. You comfy?
太挤了
If I could have a little more room...
没地方了
Well, there isn't any.
这里有好东西 手铐啊
There's a lot of shit in here. We got handcuffs in here.
这罐子里是什么？
What's in this can?
除口臭的
That's for your breath.
挤一点到你嘴巴里
You could use it, squirt some in your mouth.
那是美斯 不是吗？
Yeah, well, that's mace, isn't it?
好吧！你 去……
嘿
Hey.
你的枪呢？你的手枪
Where's your gun? Your pistol?
在车里 我的包里
In my bag, in the car.
要命 这里真臭
Boy, it stunk in there.
我想是的 你把我爸给我的值900元的套装弄坏了
I believe it. You're ruining a $900 suit my dad gave me.
它和那只12口径的枪很配
Yeah, it went great with that 12-Gauge, too.
像你这种人怎么会当法警
Why in the world would someone like you become a federal marshal?
专门抓你这种人
The idea of going after guys like you appealed to me.
那是什么意思？
Sorry, what was that?
像我这种人！让我告诉你吧
Guys like me? Let me tell you something.
虽然我近来单身
Even though I've been celibate lately,
但是我不是非要缠着你不可
I'm not gonna force myself on you.
我从没做过
I've never done that in my life.
你不会有时间做
You wouldn't have time anyway.
碰到路障 他们查车后就
We come to a roadblock, they run the car
会知道这是谁的车了
and find out in about five seconds who it belongs to.
即使他们要设的话 我怀疑他们能否及时设一个
Yeah, that's if they get one set up in time, which I doubt. If they do,
他们要找两个拉丁人
they're gonna be lookin' for a bunch of little Latin fellas,
而不是个黑大个
not a big black guy driving a Ford.
他真是你的好兄弟 如此拿自己来牺牲
Karen: He must be quite a pal, to risk his own ass like this.
巴蒂 他是个好家伙
Jack: Buddy? Yeah, he's a good guy.
我们一起坐牢时
Back when we jailed together,
他每周一定打电话给他姐姐
he used to call his sister every week, without fail.
她是重生的基督徒
She's a born-again Christian.
给电视布道家记账
You know, she does bookkeeping for a televangelist.
他会打电话向她忏悔
He 'd call her up, confess his sins.
告诉他抢过的银行
He 'd tell her whatever bank he happened to Rob at the time.
巴蒂是他的名字吗？
Karen: Buddy, that his given name?
对！我给他取得
Jack: The one igave him, yeah.
你叫什么？
Karen: So what's your name?
明天看报就知道了
Be in the paper tomorrow anyway.
杰克弗里 你恐怕听过
Jack foley. You've probably heard of me.
为什么 你很有名吗？
Why? Are you famous?
我在加州被判刑时
The time I was convicted in California,
调查局说我抢银行的纪录比谁都多
the F.B.I. Told me that I'd robbed more banks than anybody in the computer.
多少次？
How many was that?
我真的不知道
Tell you the truth, I don't really know.
我18岁时
I started when I was 18 years old,
开始替我叔叔卡利和他搭档开车
driving for my uncle cully, and his partner, Gus.
你是说你半辈子都在牢里
So basically you're saying you spent half your life in prison.
对 如果再被逮住 要关30年
Basically, yeah. If I go back, I do 30 years, no time off.
你能想象吗？
You imagine looking at that?
我不用想 我又不抢银行
I don't have to. I don't Rob banks.
你好像一点都不怕
Jack: You don't seem all that scared.
我当然怕 看不出来
- Of course I am. - You don't act like it.
你要我大叫吗？
What do you want me to do, scream?
那也起不了作用
That wouldn't help much anyway.
我打算坐在这里
No, I'm just gonna sit here, take it easy,
等你自己搞砸
and wait for you to screw up.
听起来像我前妻
Jack: You sound like my ex-wife.
你结过婚
You were married?
一年左右
For about a year, give or take a few days.
我们相处得不错 只是……
It's not like we didn't get along. We had fun. We just...
没有那种……
Didn't have that thing, you know, that, uh,
激情 那很重要
uh, you know, that spark. You know? Gotta have that.
嗯哼
Uh-huh.
尽管我们仍在说话
We still talk, though.
是吗？
Sure.
你是不会有好下场的 做这种事永远都不会有
Karen: This is not gonna end well. These things never do.
我要死也想被人打死在大街上
Turns out I get shot like a dog, it's gonna be in the street,
不想死在牢里
not off a goddamn fence.
你真以为你是什么克莱贝罗
You must really see yourself as some kind of Clyde barrow, huh?
你是指邦尼和克莱
You mean, of Bonnie and Clyde?
是的
- Yeah. - Yeah, yeah.
电影中他们中弹 华伦比提和……
That part in the movie where they get shot, when it's Warren Beatty and...
费唐 娜薇  费唐 娜薇 yeah.
- Faye dunaway. - Faye dunaway. Yeah.
我喜欢她演的
I like her in that movie about TV.
“电视网”
- Network. - Yeah.
演得真好
Yeah, she was good.
那家伙说他再不吃那套
And that guy who says he's not gonna take any more shit from anybody.
彼特 芬奇  Yeah！ 彼特 芬奇
- Peter Finch. - Yeah! Peter Finch.
“我已经火大了 我不会吃你那套”
"I'm mad as hell, and I'm not gonna take any more of your shit!"
在他们中枪的那一节 我记得我一直在想……
In the part where they get shot, I remember thinking to myself, thinking
如果你别无选择的时候 这个结局也不算太坏
you know, that it wouldn't be such a bad way to go, if you had to.
你很会和人聊天
Jack: You sure are easy to talk to.
如果我们在不同的场合下遇到
I was thinking, if we met under different circumstances,
你在酒吧 我出现 我们交谈
if you were in a bar and I came up and we started talking,
然后呢？没有了
- I wonder what would happen. - Nothing.
如果你不知道我是谁
If you didn't know who I was.
你可能会告诉我
You'd probably tell me.
如果场合不同……
I'm just saying if we met under different circumstances...
-你在开玩笑 -是
- You have got to be kidding. - Yeah.
是
Yeah.
我喜欢另一部费唐娜薇演的电影是《三日兀鹰》
Another movie I liked with Faye dunaway was three days of the condor.
劳伯瑞夫年轻时拍的那部
The one with Robert redford when he was young.
是
Yeah.
那部电影一点意思都没有
You know, I never thought it made sense though.
他们那么快就好上了
You know, the way they got together so quick.
是嘛？
Really?
很浪漫  嗯哼
- I mean, romantically. - Hm.
可是……
Well, but, if...
All right. Here we go. Where the hell are we?
又停了 我们现在在哪里?
公路收费口 葛兰在上面另一辆车里
Buddy: At the turnpike. Glenn's right above us with the other car.
快出来！ 背过身举起手
Jack: All right, come on, hop on out.
快出来！背过身举起手
Turn around and get your hands up, now!
别管她 反正我们也不要这辆车了
Buddy: We may as well leave her. We're ieavin' the car
我们总要把她甩了
and we gotta leave her some place anyway. What's the difference where?
她得跟著我们
She's coming with us.
天啊 你在那里搞什么?
Jesus Christ, what were you doing in there?
找名字  找过了
- Looking for a name. - I already looked.
她叫凯伦西思科
Her name is Karen sisco.
像席司科孩童 拼法不同
Like the Cisco kid, only spelled different.
凯伦?
S-i-s-c-o.
凯伦
Karen?
你要老实一点
All right, Karen? Now you be a good girl now.
我要打开后车盖了
I'm gonna open up the trunk.
喂！ 喂！ 喂！
Hey, hey, hey, hey, now!
你在往自己车上打窟窿
Now you're putting holes in your car!
我不会把你扔在这里
I'm not ieavin' you.
我要开后车盖 你把枪扔出来
I'm gonna open up the trunk just enough for you to drop your pistol out.
巴蒂有你的猎枪 你要开枪的话 他会射回去
If you shoot, buddy's got your shotgun. He's gonna shoot back.
我拦不住他 就看你自己了
There's nothing I can do about it, so it's up to you.
嘿！嘿！
Glenn: Hey. Hey!
别开枪！是葛兰
Don't! It's Glenn! Whoa!
妈的 杰克 很高兴见到你
Fuck! Hey, hey, Jack. Good to see you, man.
你们在射谁?
What the fuck are you guys shooting at?
我们要他吗?
Do we need him?
警察见过这辆车
The cop saw this car.
他可能会起疑心再调回头
He might tie it to the break and turn around.
好吧
All right.
嘿 小伙子 我们没认出你
Hey, studs. We didn't recognize you.
嘿 “小伙子 ”
Hey, "studs," man.
从兰坡出来後就没有听过混得怎么样?
I haven't heard that since lompoc, man. So what's going on?
没怎么样
Oh, nothing.
凯伦 你要出来吗?
Karen. Are you coming out?
听到了吗？好吧
- You hear that? - Karen: Okay.
—听到了吗？好吧
Okay.
算你赢 杰克
You win, Jack.
衣服乾洗完后 帐单寄给我
When you get your clothes cleaned, you send me the bill.
我会寄到葛雷兹去
I'll send it to you at glades.
你是不是刚从阴沟洞里爬出来?你是谁?
Did you crawl through a sewer, man? Who're you?
摘下墨镜
Take your sunglasses off.
戴著看得更清楚
I see better with them on, man, hey...
小心我把你和墨镜一起扔到天桥上去
You don't take 'em off, I'm gonna throw 'em off the overpass
等在车里
while they're still on your head. Go wait in the car.
文明社会里 说话客气点
Um, we're in civilization now, so you can ease up just a little...
对不起 请你在车里等
I'm sorry. I'd like you to wait in the car, please.
带上她 放在后座！
Take her, put her in the back.
后车厢？
Okay. In the trunk?
后坐！
In the backseat! In the backseat!
过来！ 因为我要……
Okay, you gotta come now, 'cause I got to do...
把外套给我！
Hang on, wait, I need yourjacket. Gimme yourjacket.
我需要干净衣服
Somebody forgot to bring me clean clothes.
干净衣服在凯迪拉克车里
Buddy: I brought 'em, they're at glades, in the back of the Cadillac.
是你自己要跳进她的后车箱
You decided to jump into the trunk of her car.
你可以怪我 我不介意
You can blame me if you want. I don't mind.
—给你：我要告诉你……
- Here, sir. - I tell you, I...
你有什么毛病?
What's your problem, Jack?
你为什么叫葛兰来
I don't know why you got Glenn involved in this.
这件事是他的主意
How 'bout the score was his idea to begin with?
他?
Idea?
他没有脑子的
The guy's got a fucking vacant lot for a head.
他以为他可以用这种口气跟我说话、He thinks he can talk to me like that? Shit.
“把外套给我”我坐在这里等了半个钟头
"Give me yourjacket." I have been sitting here for over a half-hour,
防备著警察 你以为那是好玩的?
watching out for the highway patrol. You think that's fun?
天哪
God.
我得钻进灌木丛……
You know, I had to go over there in the bushes
抽根大麻 这样我才能…
to smoke a joint, just so I could, like...
你知道吗?
You know?
对 我在北部有大计划
Yep. I got something big lined up up north.
如果没有我 这些家伙怎么可能知道
These guys wouldn't even fuckin' know about it, if it wasn't for me.
他一讲话我就想揍他
Every time he opens his mouth, I want to punch him out.
他不是问题
He's not the problem, Jack.
现在你从头到尾告诉我
Now you wanna pull your head outta your ass
你为什么要把她带著?
and tell me why the hell we're bringing her with us?
葛兰
- Glenn. - You know my... what?
你不记得我了吗?
You don't remember me, do you?
我从未进过葛雷兹 如果你是这个意思的话
Um, couldn't've been glades, if that's what you're thinking,
因为我从来没有在外面
'cause I was never out there.
我不是这个意思
No, that's not what I'm thinking.
哦 是吗？
Oh, yeah?
但你肯定我们见过?
But you're sure we've met, huh?
去年秋天
Last fall.
我押著你从棕榈滩县监狱
I drove you from the palm beach county jail
到联邦法院 两次
to the federal courthouse twice.
你是葛兰麦克
You're Glenn Michaels.
我从不忘记我逮过的任何人
I never forget anybody I've cuffed and shackled.
让我们来想想办法 葛兰
Now, let's think about this for a minute, Glenn, see if we can't work it out.
车里有枪吗？
Do we have a gun in the car?
见鬼 我记起来了
Oh, shit! I remember you!
弗理不会有好下场的 他完蛋 你也跟著完蛋
Glenn, foley's not gonna make it. If he goes down, you go with him.
你们关系近的话我倒能了解
Now look, I can understand if you guys are close...
不 我跟他根本不熟
No, we're not.
但我现在是在帮他
But, yeah, I'm helping him.
等一下 葛兰
Now, now, wait a minute. Glenn.
你以前帮过他吗?
Have you helped him?
目前我想
I mean, technically, at this point,
你还应该不会被控“越狱共犯”的罪名
I doubt you could be charged with aiding a fugitive.
你还有机会
So you still have a choice.
你想把她带到我那里洗干净 抹上科龙水……
You want to take her to my place, get cleaned up, come out of the bathroom
出来 然後她说“原来我看错你了 ”
with your aftershave on, and she goes, "oh, I had you all wrong."
我只是想同她再聊几句
No, I just wanna talk to her again. That's all, I just...
看看在正常情况下会怎样
You know, I wanna see what it might've been like under normal circumstances.
太迟了
It's too late for that, Jack.
他想摆脱我们 我不怪他
He wants to get out of here, and I don't blame him.
两年前
在兰坡联邦监狱
如果裁判再不叫停的话
If the ref don't call it soon,
那小子要被装在裹尸袋抬出去了
snoop's gonna send this cat out in a body bag.
你知道他们为什么叫他“史努比?”
Anybody ever tell you why they call him "snoopy"?
他以前叫“疯狗”莫瑞
He used to be Maurice "mad dog" Miller,
当他还是职业拳手的时候
back when he was a pro.
现在你轻拍他 他就倒下来
Now you pet him, he goes down.
难以置信
I don't believe it!
天啊！
Oh, my!
胡闹！胡闹
好 你行
Yeah, you're the man.
那小子到处吹他
Guy's bragging he won a thrown fight.
赢了一场做假的拳赛
Fucking pathetic.
他要倒楣了
Dangerous is what it is, man.
那个秃子是谁?
Buddy: Who's the bald dude?
理查瑞利
Richard Ripley.
华尔街的?
The wall street guy?
他骗了好多人的钱 浑号骗子迪克
They call him dick the ripper, on account of all the guys he ripped off.
没戴假发我都认不出他
Buddy: Oh, yeah. I didn't recognize him without his rug.
-他被判多少年? -三年
- What's his bid? - Three years.
你们被罚了吗?
Yeah. You guys on the bench? Okay.
三年 罚金五千万 他妈的就写了张支票
Yeah, three years, fined $50 million and wrote them a fucking check.
就这样
Just like that.
五千万 签一个名而已
Fifty mill, signed his name.
还没有…对了…帮个小忙
Didn't even... didn't ev... Okay, a little help.
够了 太重
Okay, heavy! Yeah.
天！太重了
Heavy! Come on!
阳光刺眼 看不清上面的数字
With the bright glare out here, you couldn't read the numbers on the weights.
我知道了
Oh. I had it, jeez.
你怎么知道他写了张支票？
How do you know he wrote a check?
他告诉我的
Uh, he told me.
我们一起在洗衣房当差
We work laundry together.
那家伙真他妈的爱说
Guy loves to fucking talk.
他爱说：他告诉联邦检察官
Yeah, he loves to talk. He talked to the U.S. attorney.
他被那些与他做生意的人告发了
Rolled over on all the snitches he was doing business with.
有哪个家伙能拿出五千万的支票
Hey, any guy who can write a fucking check for $50 million,
他说什么我都听
he says anything, I'm all fucking ears.
他告诉我他把钱都存在外国银行
Guy tells me he's got all this money in foreign banks.
加上 大概……
Plus, around, mm,
他家里值五百万未加工的钻石
five million in uncut diamonds at his house.
他说
He said, quote,
“我可以随时动这笔钱 ”
"that I can get my hands on at any time."
他住哪里？
Where does he live?
底特律
Glenn: Detroit.
史努比米勒说未加工的钻石跟现金一样好处理
Snoopy Miller says that uncut diamonds are about as easy to move as cash.
见过未加工的钻石吗?
Ever seen an uncut diamond, studs?
就像一般石头
Looks just like a plain old rock.
慢著 你以为他在说谎?
Wait, you think this guy's lying?
你说呢?用你的大脑想一想
What do you think, studs? Use your head. Some guy's got five million dollars
如果他有五百万
socked away in his house, and he's gonna tell some motormouth
他会告诉你这样在监狱里的大嘴巴?
he just met in prison about it?
我就知道你们不会相信我
Oh, I see. You guys are cynical. Right.
来了
Here it comes.
别停下 继续走
Keep on walking. Keep walking.
你别回答任何问题
You don't wanna be answering any questions.
我只是说她一点都不怕
Jack: I'm just saying she wasn't scared, that's all.
那是因为她一直把手放在枪上
Buddy: That's 'cause she had her hand on her gun the whole time
等待采取行动
waiting to make a move.
你是嫉妒你没有在后车箱跟她在一起 不是你
Jack: You're just jealous because it was me in the trunk with her, not you.
对了
Buddy: You're right.
让我先把自己弄干净
First thing I'm gonna do is get this mud off me.
喂
Hey.
凯伦 凯伦 亲爱的?
Marshall: Karen. Karen, honey?
凯伦
Karen.
你说梦话
You were talking in your sleep.
我说了甚么
What'd I say?
“嘿 你自己 ”
"Hey, yourself."
喂
Huh.
喂 丹尼尔
Hello, Daniel.
丹尼尔波顿 联邦调查局
Daniel burdon, F.B.I.
联邦警察西思柯 凯伦的父亲
Marshall sisco, Karen's dad.
请你在外面等等
Would you mind, please, waiting outside?
我们有事要谈
We have some business to do here.
反正我要上厕所 对不起
Well, uh, I have to use the John anyway. Excuse me.
- Yeah. - Mm-hm.
我要加入特勤小组 丹尼尔
I wanna be on the task force, Daniel.
嗯-
Well.
谢谢你的好意 但是……
That's nice of you to offer, Karen, but...
我已有足够的人力
I got all the help I can use right now.
让我们谈一下你头上的包是怎么来的
Instead, let's talk about how you got that bump on your head.
你手上拿的不是我的卷宗吗?
Isn't that my file you're holding onto?
是的 但是我要听你亲口讲
Yes, but I want to hear it from you,
从你和他抢驾驶盘开始
starting with when you grabbed the wheel.
这是在那儿?
Where was this?
快到欧基乔比出口的地方
Coming to the okeechobee exit.
坐好！
Glenn: Sit back!
你戴著墨镜 能看得到吗?
Karen: Can you see with those glasses on?
我很好！这…真笨
Yes, I'm fine! This is stupid, man.
这些家伙会对我很失望
These guys are gonna be so disappointed in me, man,
你知道吗？如果不是吸了大麻
and you know what? If I wasn't stoned,
我才不会听你的
there is no way you would have talked me into this.
记住
Just remember that, all right?
过了桥就从这里出去
Get off at the exit right after that bridge.
我不会去自首
No, I am not! I am not fucking turning myself in,
所以忘记它，好吗？
so forget it, all right?
往那边开  哪边?
- Get off at that exit! - What exit? I don't even...
那边的出口 坐好！
- That exit right there! - Sit back!
- 走出口！ - 不！
- Take the exit! - No!
当我清醒时
Karen: Next thing I knew,
救护人员把我从车里拖出来
the paramedics were pulling me out of the car.
你还好 有几个问题我怀疑的是……
Daniel: There's a couple of points ikeep wondering about
有关那两个捉你的家伙
that have to do with the two guys who grabbed you.
是巴蒂?和这个家伙杰克弗理
Buddy, is it? And this fella, Jack foley.
这个人起码已抢了200家银行
I swear, the man must have robbed over 200 banks in his time.
啊？
- Really? - Mm-hm.
他告诉我他记不得抢了多少家
He told me he didn't remember how many he robbed.
那你和他谈过话
Then you talked to him.
在后车箱里 是啊
In the trunk, yeah.
你们谈甚么?
What'd you talk about?
各种事
Different things.
监狱 电影
Prison, movies.
这家伙绑架你 你还跟他谈电影?
This fella holds you hostage, you talk about movies?
这是个不平凡的经验
It was an unusual experience.
弗理让我想起卡尔提门
You know, foley made me think of that fella Carl tillman.
你去看时 他刚巧在抢银行
The one that you were seeing, it turns out the same time he was robbing banks.
你记不记得?
Do you recall that?
卡尔怎么了?
And what happened to Carl?
你对他开枪
Oh, the time came, you shot him.
但是你没打弗理和他的朋友
But you didn't shoot foley or the guy with him.
他们没带武器 你有散弹枪
They're unarmed. You had a shotgun
却让他们把你丢进后车箱
and you let them throw you in the trunk.
你手上有西格手枪
Okay? Now you got your sig in your hand
你在报告中说你不能回头
and you say in the report that you couldn't turn around,
他把你牵制住了
he had you pinned down.
但是当车箱打开时
But when the trunk opened,
为什么你不打死他们?
how come you didn't cap the two guys then?
你平常做什么？
What do you work on most of the time?
捉做手脚的簿记人员?
Fraud? Go after crooked bookkeepers?
我在局里十五年 参加过各种不同的调查
Karen, I've been with the bureau 15 years on all kinds of investigations.
曾经射杀过人没有？没有
- Have you ever shot a man? - No.
你有没有带头破门而入过?
When was the last time you were primary through the door?
我还要资格审查?
I have to qualify? Is that it?
你必须知道你自己在说什么
You have to know what you're talking about.
下次再谈
We'll talk another time. All right, Karen?
奇怪！为什么弗理在不需要你的时候
I'd like to know why foley put you in that second car
还把你放进第二辆车……
when he didn't need you anymore.
那你只有去问他自己了
You'll have to ask him that.
Rip, rip.
谈个交易怎么样?
What the deal is, baby?
嗨 莫瑞
Hi, Maurice.
我不知道  来敲敲手
- Oh. I don't know. - Make a fist.
又来了
There you go.
走开
Fuck it, man.
我拿到你要的金鱼了
Got your little fishies for you.
好
Oh, good.
慢点
Not so fast. See starting out,
价钱涨了
there's gonna be an across the board cost of living increase, know what I mean?
什么？
What?
我是因信用欺诈被抓进来的
You know, when I got put in here a year ago on credit card fraud
不过只是个小角色
I didn't really get no props for that, you know?
但自从我在院子里
But ever since I shanked that loudmouth pussy in the yard the other day,
捅了那个大嘴巴後
it's like my dun and broadstreet 'round this bitch shot way the fuck up, man.
我的名声大涨 变成大英雄了
Actually, it's dun and bradstreet, that's the, urn...
我都听说了
Well, I've heard it both ways.
最重要的是 价钱涨了
Point is that the price has gone up around this bitch too, okay?
把你的黑册子拿出来我们要办正事
So get your black book out. We got some business to talk about.
这些鱼 我以前讲的价钱是
All right, for the little fishies... What'd I say they was gonna be?
两千  现在是三千
- Two thousand. - Two thousand? Yeah, okay.
现在是三千
Now they're gonna be three thousand.
什么…
Come on...
现在是三千
Now they're gonna be three thousand.
那些滴在你眼睛里的狗屎盐水
That saltwater shit that you put in your eyes?
你叫它们什么?
What do you call that?
眼药水
- Bausch & lomb. - Bauschie lomb?
- Yeah. - All right.
那些狗屎眼药水 是三百块
That bauschie lomb shit. That's 300.
我要
I need it.
对 你要 另外那个枕头
Yeah, you do. And that extra pillow you want,
我会帮你搞到 但要五百块
I'm gonna get that for you, but that's gonna be like five c's.
五百?
- Five? - Jack: Hey.
标志上说禁止讲话 你们不识字吗?
Sign says shut the fuck up, or can't you fellas read?
你他妈的和谁讲话?
Who the fuck you talkin' to, man?
弗理 你有什么问题吗?
You got a problem over there, foley?
是的 我有一个问题
Yeah, I got a problem.
这是我看过最笨的一个敲诈
This is the dumbest shakedown in the history of dumb shakedowns.
五百块一个枕头
Five hundred bucks for a pillow?
对啊 是有点太贵了
- That's right. - It does seem a little high, doesn't it?
闭嘴 迪克
Shut up, dick.
一定是好枕头
Jack: Must be a nice pillow.
高级鹅毛的
Faux goose down.
但是…
But still...
你们一夥赚多少?
How much for your company at chow?
我们一夥?我得看著这狗娘养的
My company? Come on, man, you know I watch this motherfucker's back.
多少?
I bet. How much?
100块
That's a c-note.
瑞利 叫这家伙滚开
You're smart, Ripley, you'll tell this guy to fuck off.
真的？
Really?
我不知道
Well, I don't know.
他杀了你 什么也得不到
First of all, if he kills you, then he's gonna get nothing.
不必杀他 弗理
Well, uh, the man don't just have to die, foley.
他可能跌倒在硬东西上
I mean, he could accidentally hurt himself
伤到自己
falling down on something real hard, you know?
像刀或我的老二甚么的
Like a shiv. Or my dick.
我付钱 我付钱 别担心
I'll pay. I'll pay it. Don't worry.
如果他跌倒 史努比
If he falls on anything, snoop,
他会很快被转监 快到你想不到
then they're gonna transfer his ass outta here faster than you can throw a fight
你还是甚么也得不到
and you're still gonna get nothing.
上次我查过
You know, last time I checked, man,
这与你无关
this shit over here didn't have nothing to do with you, foley.
出去抽根烟或甚么的
Why don't you go outside, man, smoke a cigarette or some shit?
我不抽烟
I don't smoke.
你听到他啦 快滚吧
You heard the man. Why don't you get your punk ass up out of here?
Uh-oh.
你惨了 那是海米
You fucked up now, man. That's himey.
我的保镖 这监狱的第32号狠人物
Protégé of mine. Ranked number 32 in the federal prison system.
32？ 对
- 32? - Maurice: That's right.
在多少 20个人里面?
Out of, what, 20?
扁他
- Ripley: Oh, that's a funny one. - Man, kick this cracker's ass.
这里发生了甚么事?
What's going on here?
没事
Nothing, you know.
在看“如何读书”甚么的结果大家都兴奋起来了
Just "reading is fundamental" and shit. We just got all excited and everything.
全出去 现在
- Right there. - Clear outta here. Now.
没问题  全都走
- No problem. - All of you. Let's go.
我想买鱼的事定了 史努比
Uh, snoopy. I think we, uh, settled the fish thing.
这鱼 喔！对不起……
Oh, the fish. Yeah. My bad.
这是我们握手的方法 老弟
That's how you do the shake, partner.
报上说你们各悬赏一万  —奇诺和陆露
Buddy: Paper says there's ten grand each on you, chino, and Lulu.
他们有没有提到凯伦
They say anything about Karen?
只说她跑了
Just that she got away. Here.
杰克
- Hm? - Jack!
没关系
That's all right. It's in the pool.
有没有说她和葛兰走了以後怎样?
Did it say what happened to her after she took off with Glenn?
你得问葛兰
I don't know, Jack. You'll have to ask Glenn.
他可能正在去底特律的路上 我们也该去
And he's probably on his way to Detroit, which is where we should be.
好
Yeah.
你知道你在干么吗?
Do you realize what you're doing, Jack?
这女人是执法人员
Worrying about a woman who works for law enforcement?
你想和对你开枪的女人喝鸡尾酒?
You wanna sit down and have cocktails with a woman who tried to shoot you.
你在听吗?
Do you hear what I'm saying?
你想这老家伙是她男朋友?
Do you think this old guy right there is her boyfriend?
只有这张相片
It's the only picture she has in here.
我一个人去底特律?
Am I going to Detroit by myself?
待在这儿越久 就越可能……
Jack, the longer we stay here, the better the chance is
葛兰可能搞砸
that either Glenn is gonna screw up the score,
也可能我们被捕 或两个都是
or we gonna get busted, or both.
这是弗理?
Marshall: This is foley?
凯伦?
- Karen. - Hm?
这是弗理?
This is foley?
一点也不像……
He doesn't even look like that.
不像?
- Oh, no? - Mmm-mmm.
他看起来比较像……
He looks a lot like...
不一样
Different.
怀特尔普来了
Wyatt earp is here.
怀特
Wyatt, h u h?
-嗨  -嗨
- Hey. - Hey.
-感觉怎样? -还好
- How you feeling? - Good.
-好一点了吗?  -是的
- You feel better? - Yeah.
你父亲照顾你?
Is your dad taking good care of you?
他请假一礼拜…
He took the week off
想照顾我 但他却只在修他的船
to take care of me and he's worked on his boat every day since.
这是雷尼可 嗨
Dad, this is ray nicolet.
我听了好多关于你的事
Pleasure to meet you. I heard a lot about you.
彼此彼此
Likewise.
雷正与调查局特勤小组一同调查越狱案
Ray's working with the F.B.I. Task force on the prison break.
我看到
I see that.
告诉我 雷 你有没有穿过“便衣”字样的衣服?
Tell me, ray, do you ever wear one that says "undercover"?
没有  事情进展如何?
How's it going?
坐下来
Sit down.
不错
Okay.
我们捉到其中一个
Good. Good, we caught one of them.
-是弗理吗? -从线民的线索来的
- Was it foley? - Was it off a tip?
有人在机场附近看到他们俩个
Yeah. Somebody spotted two of them out in this hobo camp near the airport.
打了报案电话
You know, called in the number.
是悬赏起了作用
I knew it as soon as I saw there was a reward.
是弗理吗?
Babe, was it foley?
不是 是里纳兹 古巴帮中的一个
Ray: No, linares, one of the Cubans.
我们与霹雳小组 两架直升机一起攻进去
We went in there, you know, full SWAT, two choppers, that whole deal.
里纳兹开始开枪 所以我们先逮他
Linares goes nuts, starts shooting, so we took him out.
奇诺溜了
I don't know how, but chirino got away.
弗理不在现场
And foley hadn't been there?
只有古巴人而已
Ray: No, this place was strictly Cubans.
弗理搭了车 他一定另有计划
You know, foley had a ride. He must have his own agenda. You know what I mean?
他好像是唯一知道自己在干什么的人
He seems to be the only guy who kinda knows what he's doing.
Uh-huh.
对不起
Excuse me.
Yeah.
喂？
Hello?
她在 请等一下
Yeah, she is. Just a minute, please.
凯伦
Mm-hm. Karen.
喂？嗨！
- Helll. O
你知道我是谁吗?
you know who this is?
知道 五分钟
Yes. Five minutes.
那么 雷
- So, ray. - Yeah.
有些事我感到奇怪
There's something I'm wondering.
报纸标题说有个迈阿密女人说她同杀人犯睡觉
The headline reads, "I slept with a murderer, says shaken Miami woman."
谁接的电话
Jack: Who was it that answered the phone?
与你无关
None of your business.
可能对你来说我还不够成熟
I'm just worried maybe I'm not old enough for you.
-那是我父亲 -真的?
- It was my dad. - Really?
他一脸警察相
He's got a cop's face.
你怎么会知道?
How do you know?
你拿了我的皮夹
Oh, wait. You have my wallet.
还有你的枪
And your gun.
我可以拿回来吗?
Think I can have 'em back?
要怎么做?
How do we do that?
来我父亲家 丢在他那里
Oh, let's see, you can come on by my dad's place and drop 'em off.
我干脆给应门的霹雳小组特警算了
Yeah, I can leave 'em with the SWAT guy that answers the door.
现在有个特勤小组的家伙在这里
You know, there's a guy here on the task force right now.
也许我该让他讲
Maybe I should put him on the phone and let the two of you work it out.
你不会这样做
You wouldn't do that.
为什么不？
Oh, why not?
你玩得很愉快嘛
Because you're having too much fun.
她替他煮了猪排饭
She fixes him pork chops and rice.
接著 他们就在沙发上做爱
The next thing you know, they're making love on the sofa.
她说他很温柔
She says he was very gentle.
奇里诺来了 说他想他的小女人
This guy chirino shows up at the house, says he misses his little girl.
她觉得对不起他 接著…砰
She feels sorry for him. Next thing you know, boom!
在沙发上
You know? On the couch.
这就是你们目前的进展?
That's how you score now, huh?
是吧
I guess.
我一直在想些事
There's something I've been wondering.
你的卡利叔呢?
Whatever happened to your uncle cully?
希望他告诉你我在哪?
Why, you think he's gonna tell you where I am?
除非你要
Unless you want to tell me.
他死了
He's dead.
坐了27年车
Did 27 years before he got out,
出狱几年后 死在慈善医院
and he died a couple years afterwards in a charity hospital
弥补所有他错过的好时光
while trying to make up for all the good times he missed.
我绝不会那么做
That's not gonna be me.
最后一搏 退休到某小岛?是嘛?
Oh, what, one last score, retire to some island? Is that the idea?
杰克
Jack.
我本身偏爱山区
I'm partial to mountains myself,
不过你喜欢小岛 我们就去小岛
but if you like islands, we'll make it an island.
“我们”是指?
What do you mean, "we'll make it an island"?
我和你可以…
You and I can make it...
你最好来看看
Jack, you better come check this out.
那是巴蒂吗?
Is that buddy?
-什么?好 拜拜 -你在跟谁说话？
- What? No. Okay. Bye-bye. - Who are you talking to?
所以 她已婚了  正确
- So she's a married woman. - Right.
她和逃犯上床 因为……
But she goes to bed with a prison escapee because
他说他想念他的小女人
he tells her that he misses his little girl.
她告诉全世界的人 但你却保护她
She tells the world about it. But you protect her.
你没泄漏她的姓名
You don't reveal her name.
听起来她做得不错
Well, that makes it sound like what she was doing was okay
只要她老公没发现
as long as her husband doesn't find out about it.
就像偷腥的家伙说
Like the guy who cheats on his wife
老婆不知情就不受伤
saying what she doesn't know won't bother her.
爸  干嘛？
- Dad. - What?
雷 让你看个东西 在客厅里
Ray, I wanna show you something in the living room.
很高兴跟你聊天
- Yeah. - Good talking to you, ray.
我也是
Yeah, you too.
今天早上 联邦警察临检
Newscaster: Federal law enforcement agents raided a squatters camp
一个在迈阿密国际机场北边的
north of Miami international airport this morning
流浪汉聚所搜寻
in the hopes of capturing a fugitive
周二从葛雷兹监狱脱逃的逃犯
from Tuesday's daring escape from glades prison.
其中一名 奥里李纳兹
F.B.I. Officials confirm that one of the escapees, aurelio linares,
被杀死
was killed...
奇诺会找我
Jack: Chino's gonna wanna talk to me.
奇诺忙著逃命 根本不甩你
Man, chino's runnin' for his life. He don't give a shit about you.
他会知道我放弃他了 他会要找我
He's gonna know by now I gave him up back at glades. He's gonna wanna find me.
也许问阿黛儿 看她知道什么?
Maybe go see Adele, see what she knows.
他知道她住哪?
He knows where she lives?
杰克！
Jack.
我们曾一起聊天喝过酒
We were talking once, drinking rum,
我可能提过她
and I may have mentioned Adele.
她曾替魔术师工作过 他很感兴趣
How she worked for a magician. Chino got all interested.
他说 “你怎么把女人锯成两半？”
He said, "how do you saw the woman in half?"
当她来探监时 他想见见她
He wanted to meet her, see her if she came to visit.
所以你打了电话 要她不要跟古巴帮讲话
Okay, okay. So you call her up. Tell her don't talk to any Cubans.
电话可能被监听了
The phone's probably tapped by now.
你是对的 如果手机被窃听
Yeah, you're right and if the phone is tapped,
你就知道他们已经锁定了这个地方
you know they have the place staked out.
该死
Shit!
阿黛儿 德利西
Adele delisi speaking.
是阿黛儿吗?
Chino: Oh, oh, this is Adele?
是啊！
Oh, yes, it is.
抱歉  打错了
Oh, oh, sorry. Wrong number.
乔装得不错
Nice disguise.
我是个观光客
I'm a tourist.
你看
All right, here we go.
前面这里左手边
Coming up right here on the left.
那个剪树丛的家伙?
Clock the guy with the clippers
我想联邦调查局…剪树丛要收多少钱?
Jack: Man, I wonder what the F.B.I. Is charging to trim hedges these days.
棋下得有模有样
Buddy: Quite a checker game they got goin' on too.
靠边停
Jack: Pull on up.
噢！天啊
Jack: Oh, man.
Oh, man.
你看得到却得不到
Okay, you saw her. That's all you get.
我们去底特律吧
Let's go to Detroit.
你总算说了句人话
Now you're talkin', brother.
我得替杰克说句话 他很体贴
Adele: I'll say one thing for Jack, he's very considerate.
嗯 时好时坏的
Lights on or off, if you know what I mean?
是啊
Really? Hm.
阿黛儿 听著
Adele, listen.
我只是想在事情搞得更糟前
I just want to find him before he does something else
找到他
and makes it worse on himself.
巴蒂会照顾他
Buddy'll take care of him.
不让他惹麻烦 他是杰克的良知
Keep him out of trouble. He's Jack's conscience, always has been.
他们大概一起抢过50家银行
They must have robbed 50 banks together.
是最佳拍档
They were a really great team.
直到他们被抓
- Until they got busted. - Mm.
那不是杰克的错 那是因为……
That wasn't Jack's fault. No, that was on account of buddy.
巴蒂 他决定在他们行动之前
For some reason, he decided to call his sister and confess to the job
向他姊姊坦白
before they'd done it instead of after.
她打给联邦调查局 结果两个都进了兰坡
Well, she called the F.B.I. They both went down and they ended up at lompoc.
我想巴蒂有点愧疚
I think buddy felt kind of bad about that.
阿黛儿 你知道在哪儿可找到巴蒂?
Adele, do you have any idea where I could find buddy?
或葛兰?
Or Glenn?
米拉 阿黛儿 在吗?
Chino: Mira, Adele, you in there?
在
Yes.
米拉 我想和你谈谈
Chino: Mira, I'd like to speak to you, please.
你是谁?
Well, who is it?
伊米 你以前的老板
Emile, you know the guy you used to work for?
Uh-huh.
他给我你的电话和地址 米拉
Chino: He gave me your number and where you live. Mira.
我在找助理 我能和你谈谈吗?
I'm looking for an assistant. Can I speak to you, please?
好
Oh, uh, yeah.
你替伊米工作过?
Chino: You did work for Emile, right?
我当过伊米四年的盒装美人
Yeah, I was Emile's boxjumper for four years almost.
你是什么?他的盒子?
Chino: You were what? His box?
他的助理
- Adele: His assistant. - Chino: Oh.
你说你在迈阿密表演?
You say you perform in the Miami area?
到处都去
Chino: Oh, si, you know, here, there, you know, at a...
我在古巴是魔术师
I was a magician in Cuba.
他们都叫我“蛮牛”魔术师
They used to call me manuelito the magician.
米拉 开个门
Mira, can you please open?
我没穿衣服
I'm not dressed.
我是杰克弗理的好友
Chino: I'm... I'm a good friend of Jack foley.
你认识杰克?
You know Jack?
你是谁?
Who are you?
荷西奇里诺
Chino: Jose chirino.
也许你听过杰克叫我奇诺 我就是
Maybe you heard Jack call me chino. Bueno. I'm the same guy.
叫他等等：你要穿衣服
Tell him that he has to wait in the hall. That you have to get dressed. Say it loud.
在外面等 你要穿衣服
Wait in the hall. You have to get dressed.
告诉我哪里找得到杰克 我就不再烦你
Mira, Mira, you tell me where to find Jack and I don't bother you no more.
好啦！拜托
Come on, please!
Hello?
我不知道他在哪
I don't know where he is.
我帮过杰克逃狱 米拉
Chino: I'm that guy that helped Jack escape from prison. Mira.
打开这该死的门……
Please open this fucking door...
我要叫警察了
Go away because I'm gonna call the police.
为什么要那样对杰克的朋友?
Chino: Why you gonna do that, man, to a friend, man?
你是其中的一员吗 杰克？
Are you part of this, Jack?
够了
That's it! That's it!
米拉 拜托！
Mira, please. Please.
阿黛尔！阿黛尔！手给我
- Adele! - Karen: Give me your hand.
你不是阿黛尔
Adele! You not Adele!
联邦警察 你被拘捕了
I'm a federal marshal and you're under arrest.
把皮包给我 阿黛儿
- Get my bag, Adele. - Oh.
米拉 拜托！
Chino: Mira, please, please.
我想这有些误会
I think there's a misunderstanding here. Can you...
好皮包
You got nice bag. Mira.
这件事就算了吧
Let's say we just forget about it and, uh... okay?
这件事就算了吧 我回家……
We forget about this, I go home...
闭嘴！
- Shut up. - Mi... ow!
谁该死地教你那样做?
Who the hell taught you how to do that?
另一只手给我
Give me your other hand.
-另一只手给我 -好
- Give me your other hand. - Okay, okay.
我得去小便
I gotta go make pee-pee.
你好过份
Wow! You are mean!
我要找律师
Look, I'm gonna call my lawyer.
你侵犯我的人权
This is a, what they call that? Human... Human rights violation.
丹尼尔伯波顿  凯伦西思柯
Daniel burdon, please. Karen sisco.
米拉 阿黛儿  可以问个问题吗
Mira. Adele. Adele? Can I ask you a question, please?
记得你表演的那个魔术吗?
You know that trick you do?
凯伦?
- Karen? - Mm-hm.
你在哪?我一直在找你
Where are you? I've been trying to reach you.
他们把你锯成一半时
When you're in the box and they saw you in half?
我在阿黛儿德利西家
I'm at Adele delisi's.
是魔术呀
It's magic.
我们已经找过她啦  死巷一条
We already talked to her. That's a dead end.
如果我带奇里诺回去
I was just wondering, if I brought in chirino,
你会让我加入特勤小组?
would you let me be on the task force?
当然
Daniel: Yeah, sure.
他们插入锯子 再分开盒子
They put the saw through, and separate it. And that's it. Ta-da.
不过你怎么动脚趾头?
But how do you twinkle your toes? I don't... I don't get that.
如果你带奇里诺回来 就可以加入特勤小组
You bring chirino in, and you can be on the task force.
这就是我想知道的  好
That's all I wanted to know.
别管那个前妻了
Now, would forget about the ex-wife,
回亚当斯旅馆去
and get over to the Adams hotel?
知道了
You got it.
不！
No! No!
就这样而已  是假脚
Adele: And then, that's it.
假脚?
- Fake legs. - Mm.
-谢啦 阿黛儿 -那你怎么……
- Thanks, Adele. - Fake legs? How you gonna...
Karen: Thanks, Adele.
如果是假脚 怎么能动呢?
Chino: How do they twinkle their toes then, if it's fake, Mira?
亚当斯旅馆
我们到底特律第一件事就是找葛兰
First thing we do we get to Detroit, we find Glenn,
然后把他扔出窗去
and we find a window to throw him out of.
我想 如果我是葛兰……
I was thinkin', if I was Glenn and I was up there
动了瑞利的脑筋 会去哪里
to take down the ripper, where would I go?
但如果你是葛兰 就根本不会动脑筋
Except if you were Glenn, you wouldn't be thinkin'.
记得史努比米勒 他的好兄弟?
Remember snoopy Miller, his old pal from the joint?
史努比 我以为他早已死了
Snoop, I figured he'd be brain-dead by now.
史努比不再打拳了
Nah, snoop doesn't box anymore.
葛兰说他在克朗克做几个拳击手的经纪人
Glenn told me that he managing some fighters out at the kronk.
拿到钥匙了?
Did you get the key?
他们在613房
They're in room 613.
两个人在外面 守著前后门
I want two men outside, front and back.
康诺、杰森 上六楼 掩护走廊两端
Conroy, Jameson, go on up to six. Cover both ends of the hall.
你先走 你殿后
You're primary. You're secondary.
你把哨
And you're point man.
你要用撞门桩吗?
You gonna use a ram?
对 干嘛?
Yeah. Why?
经理的门是铁的
The manager's door is metal.
说不定全是
You know what I mean? They might all be.
桩打在铁门上制造噪音而已
A ram on a metal door makes a lot of noise for what good it does.
我的散弹枪里有破锁弹
I got a shock lock round for my shotgun, oughta do the trick.
好 随便
Fine. Whatever.
二楼 谢谢
Two, please.
你
Can you?
走楼梯吧
Fuck it. Let's take the stairs.
凯伦！凯伦！
Karen. Karen!
待在大厅 监视电梯
Take the radio. Stay down here in the lobby and watch the elevator.
丹尼尔 我要上去
Daniel, I want to go upstairs.
你要待在车上也行
Well, you can go wait out in the car if you want to.
如果你看到弗理和柏格出现 你会怎么做?
Now, you see foley and this guy, bragg coming behind us, what do you do?
呼叫你吗?
Call and tell you?
然后让他们上来
And you let them come up.
不要自行逮捕他们 明白吗?
You don't try to make the bust yourself. You understand?
是这楼吗 女士?
Is this your floor, ma'am?
噢 是的
On! Oh, yes.
抱歉 谢谢
Yes, it is. I'm sorry. Thank you.
注意 我们接近目标门口了
Be advised we are approaching the door.
注意 要炸开门了
Be advised we are going to blow the door.
上楼吗?
Going up?
我以为是上楼
Shit, I thought I was going up.
她一直注视著我
She just looked right at me.
谁？凯伦
- Who? - Karen.
凯伦西斯柯?
- Karen sisco? - Yeah.
她在大厅
She's in the lobby.
她在大厅？对
- She's in the lobby? - Yeah.
如果他们知道我住哪 就知道我开什么车  我们得弃车
If they know where I live, no doubt they know what I drive.
她就坐在那
We gotta dump this car.
看著我
She just sat there, looking right at me.
他们不在上面 睁大眼睛
Daniel: Karen, they're not up here. Keep your eyes open.
凯伦 你在听吗？
Karen? Karen, are you there?
跟你挥手？
Marshall: He waved at you?
我肯定他有
Couldn't swear to it, but I'm pretty sure he did.
你也挥手了？
Did you wave back?
来不及了
I didn't have time.
可是我想你会的
I imagine you would have, though.
巴蒂的姊姊 维珍柏格
Buddy's sister, Regina Mary bragg,
今早接到两通巴蒂从底特律打的电话
got two calls from buddy in Detroit this morning.
她通知波顿
She calls burdon.
他还拿到巴蒂的住址  又怎样?
She's also the one who called burdon and gave him buddy's address.
在她告发他后 为什么还跟她联络?
So what I wanna know is why he still calls her after she turned him in?
他不记恨嘛
He doesn't seem to hold a grudge.
如果他们在北方有大计划
What I wanna know is why, if they got such a big score up north,
为什么弗理待在迈阿密这么久
did foley hang around in Miami for so long?
你觉得呢？
Any thoughts on that?
我不想说
None I'd like to share.
回来后我再打电话给你
I'll call you when I get in.
好吧
Okay.
底特律
真浪费时间
我不单只做买卖和管理拳击手
Maurice: You know what, I don't just deal product and manage fighters no more.
从上次见面后 很多事都变了
A lot's changed since the last time you seen me, man. It's like, I've, uh,
我把自己变得多元化
vertically integrated myself, you know, diversified and shit.
我偶尔会偷东西
And now I'm into the occasional grand larceny,
闯空门 做那些鸟事
home invasion, shit like that.
白波是我这里的跑腿
White boy Bob right there is my all-around man, you know?
需要时 还可以是保镖、司机
My personal bodyguard when I feel like I need one, driver, shit like that.
小心看路啊 白波！干嘛回头?
Yo, man, watch the road, white boy! What you iookin' back here for?
耶 耶
Yeah.
耶
我喜欢这部车 葛兰
- I like this car, Glenn. - You do?
你偷了部好车 小子
Maurice: You stole a good one, boy.
我们可以在瑞利家附近绕……
We can roll around in Ripley's neighborhood up there in bloomfield hills
不用怕私人警卫
not get sweated by the private security.
不会有警察当跟屁虫
Ain't gonna have no police on our ass,
不错吧
nothing like that. It's nice, man.
是！
Yeah.
你还没说要怎么干这件事
Oh, hey, so you still haven't said how you want to do this thing.
接到另一个兄弟后 我就一起讲
Oh. Yeah, imma tell you that as soon as we get one other brother imma need.
肯尼 那是墨塞的弟弟……
Uh, Kenneth, that's moselle's brother,
跟白波一道
along with white boy right there.
什么！
Oka... wh at?
到了 白波
All right, here we go, white boy.
那个消防员是谁？
Uh, who's the fireman?
肯尼那狗小子
Maurice: Ken dog.
怎么了 姐夫？
What's up, brother-in-law?
嘿?怎么样 大老千?
Maurice: What's happenin', hustler?
你怕闻烟味?
This cigarette gonna bother you, man?
熄了它 肯尼 这是葛兰
Yeah, put that thing out, man. Ken, this is Glenn.
葛兰 这是肯尼 我跟你提过的家伙
Glenn, that's Kenny, man, that' the dude I was tellin' you about.
- Uh.
你就是那个要帮我们打劫有钱白佬的人
You're the one gonna help us rip off that rich white dude?
就是他
Yeah, that's him.
帮你?
Help you?
开车 白波
Go ahead, white boy.
等等 看……
Um, whoa, wait a minute. Uh, look.
莫瑞 是我让你加入计划 不是……
Maurice, I am letting you in on this gig, not...
你刚问我们要怎么做
You just asked how we gonna do it, right?
我现在告诉你 我们是专家
Well, I'm telling you how, man. We're the experts.
我担心的是你 葛兰
Person I'm worried about is you, Glenn.
我？
- Me? - Yeah.
你真的可以干这档子事
Can you step up and actually do this shit, understand,
还是说说而已?
instead of just talking the talk?
干什么？
Do what?
打劫我挑中的房子
Walk into this house I got picked out.
干掉这个以前我和他交易过的黑鬼人妖
Do this cross-dressing nigga named Andy Sullivan I used to sell to.
他自己做买卖
Been dealing on his own.
什么事？甚么时候？
What? When, man?
现在 你以为做这档子事是干嘛?
Shit, right now, son. What you think all this shit is for?
我不用向你证明什么
I don't need to prove shit to you, man. Okay?
瑞利的事是我的事 要不要做随你
The Ripley job is my job. You're either in or you're not.
你想揍惹你生气的毒贩
You wanna go pop some crack dealer pissed you off,
那是你的问题 不是我的
man, that is your problem, not mine. Fuck!
我知道你酷
Glenn, I know you supposed to be cool and everything, okay,
但不要用这种口气对我说话
but you ain't got to give me no tone of voice.
你不高兴我说的
If you don't like what I'm sayin',
随时可以走
you just bounce the fuck up out this whip anywhere along up in here, man.
我想我们都忘了这是我的事
Okay, I think we're forgetting that this is my whip.
Okay?
我提起的
I brought it up.
听著 我说这是我的车 就是我的
Glenn, shit, hey, come on, man. If I say this is my car, you know this is my car.
你自己去找另一部
You just get yourself another one.
不管你要不要
If I say we in on this Ripley shit,
我们都决定进行
we in on it, with or without your punk ass.
如果我要你干掉这个混蛋
And if I say you gonna walk up in this house and do this motherfucker
来证明你有种
so I can see if you got any balls or not,
你猜你该怎么做?
guess what else you gonna do?
到了
White boy: We're here.
绑紧裤子 小子
Tighten up your panties, boy.
铁锯 我来拿
Kenneth: Hacksaw. I'll take that.
斧头
- Hatchet, man. - Hatchet?
拿斧头干嘛
What are you gonna do with a hatchet?
去好好修理那混蛋
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah. Let's set some fire to that ass.
你要．45口径还是手枪?
Look here. You want the .45 or the glock?
葛兰？
Glenn.
狗屎 小子
Maurice: Shit, boy.
比你想得更糟 对吧？
It was worse than you thought it was gonna be, huh?
现在你跟坏人一夥了
You with the bad boys now, baby.
走吧
Let's go.
你认为怎么样？
Buddy: What do you think?
我想葛兰很惊奇 我们有了另一个兄弟想加入
I think Glenn opened his big mouth and now we got ourselves another partner.
你们在这干嘛?
Hey, studs, how ya doin'?
天哪 你们在这里做什么？
Jesus Christ, what are you guys doin' here?
你在等我们吗?
Weren't you expecting us?
终于有人踩了你的墨镜
Where's your sunglasses, somebody finally step on them for you?
我不知道
I don't know.
你的衬衫上是谁的血?
Whose blood you got on your shirt?
那些家伙疯了
Listen, man, these guys are crazy.
史努比 那些家伙疯了
- Snoop! - Shit.
我们有麻烦？
We have a problem here?
杰克弗理 有名的银行大盗
Jack foley, famous bank robber.
史努比米勒 有名的拳手经纪人
Snoopy Miller, famous fight thrower.
报上说
Seems I read in the paper somewhere that,
你从佛罗里达逃狱
uh, you broke out of a prison down in Florida. Is that right?
是那样的？那里全是低级的人 史努比
- We got low class of people there, snoop. - Hey.
再叫一次 你头会撞壁
You call him that again, imma put your head through a wall.
什么? 你说“史努比?”
What? You mean "snoop"?
白波是说没人叫我史努比了
Uh, nobody calls me snoop or snoopy anymore
他只是有点粗鲁
is what white boy Bob's trying to tell you right now.
你懂嘛?
He's just a little crude with it. You know what I mean?
我全抛脑后了 伙伴
I left all that behind me, partner.
你叫这白痴“白波?”
But you call this bozo "white boy."
白波曾是个拳手
White boy Bob, white boy Bob used to be a fighter.
你现在做甚么 白波?
Oh, so tell me, what do you do now, white boy Bob,
除了射掉你的大嘴巴?
outside of shootin' your big mouth off?
像在监狱大院一样
Like being back in the yard, isn't it?
就这样
Oh, yeah, just like it.
不准退出
Nobody backing down or nothing.
谁要退出 谁就是胆小鬼
You back down, you just a pussy.
为什么你们全在底特律?
So what's up, man? Why y'all in Detroit anyway, up here in the cold?
葛兰没告诉你?
Glenn didn't tell you?
葛兰?什么?
Glenn? What?
我以为你们被抓了
I thought you guys were busted.
为什么?因为你留我们站在路旁
Why is that? 'Cause you left us standing on the side of the road?
噢
Whoops.
听著 我不知道葛兰答应了什么
Look, snoop, I don't know what Glenn promised you
也不知道你认为你会从中得到什么
or what you think you're gonna get outta this.
现在计划是
Here's the deal.
从瑞利那里得到的钱我和巴蒂拿一半
Buddy and I, we're gonna take half of anything we get off of Ripley.
其他的 你们去分
Anything else, you guys are allowed cut up any way you want.
为什么不到外面谈?
Why don't we talk about this outside, man?
这里舒服 很温暖
Nice in here. It's warm.
这里大概90度
Maurice: Warm? Shoot, it's like 90 degrees in here, man.
有时有100度以上
Sometimes it's 100 up in this mug.
因为伊曼喜欢保持这样
That's the way Emmanuel like to keep it.
把他的拳手养得瘦瘦凶凶的
Keep his fighters mean and lean, you know?
像汤米贺恩一样
Like Tommy hearns, ain't that right, Kenny?
我要去个地方
I got some place to be anyway, so tell you what.
星期五晚上来看比赛
Why don't y'all come by the fights Friday night.
我们坐下来 慢慢谈 讨论一下计划
We'll sit down, chop it up, you know, look it over.
州立剧院
State theater.
到时见
All right. We'll see you then.
拿枪打劫银行
Ripley: It must take a lot of balls to walk into a bank
一定要很大的勇气
and stick it up with a gun, huh?
我不知道 我从没用过枪
I don't know. I never used a gun before in my life.
你开玩笑
You're kidding.
如果你做得巧妙 你会得到意想不到的东西
You'd be surprised what all you can get if you ask the right way.
就因为你 我不敢把钱存在银行
Well, you're the reason, my friend, that I don't keep all my money in the bank.
那你放在哪里?
So where do you keep your money, dick?
我是说那些没加工过的钻石
Talking about all those uncut diamonds.
我知道你在说什么
I know what you're talking about.
你有胆量
You're the one with balls.
跟葛兰说过吗?
Say something like that to somebody like Glenn?
得了 谁会相信葛兰
Glenn? Come on, nobody's going to believe Glenn.
你相信他吗?
Do you believe Glenn?
我不
No, I don't.
就算是真的
Besides, even if it was true,
他也要知道我藏在哪里
he'd still have to know where I keep 'em, wouldn't he?
你跟他说藏在你家
Doesn't have to know anything. You told him you keep 'em in your house.
我家很大 你要在这儿待多久?
It's a very big house. So how much longer you in here for?
22个月 三天 两个钟头
Uh, 22 months, three days, two hours.
为什么?
Why?
因为我可以雇像你这样的人
'Cause I could use a guy like you.
一个知道怎么才能做得巧妙的人
Somebody that knows how to ask for things in the right way.
我是说在你出狱后
I'm talking about when you're out of here.
你不可能老打劫银行 对不对?
After all, you can't Rob banks forever, can you?
我可不是一个上班族
I'm not exactly a nine to five type.
谁是?
Who is?
我以为人人都喜欢艾迪
I thought everybody liked Eddie.
你好吗 雷?
How you doin', ray?
我冷死了
I'm freezing.
我可是开始暖和起来了
But I'm getting warmer.
除了上次我们合作很愉快以外
Other than we had so much fun the last time we worked together,
为什么找我 不找联邦调查局
you wanna tell me, why you're comin' to me instead of the F.B.I.?
调查局只会叫我去买咖啡
I go to the F.B.I., the first thing they're gonna do is send me to get coffee.
你知道吗?你是对的
You know what? You're right.
去年缉毒局想要抓葛兰说他持有毒品
Listen, ray, about a year ago, DEA had a guy, Glenn Michaels,
但没有成功
on possession with intent.
- 他们无法坚持下去 - 那是你的车吗？
- They couldn't make it stick. - Is that your car?
-不是我的车 -开车
- Not my car. - Find out whose it is and move it.
- All right? - All right.
葛兰说他要来底特律看朋友
In his statement he said that he was coming to Detroit to see a friend
谈有关工作的事
about job opportunities if you can believe that.
什么朋友
What was the name of the friend?
莫瑞米勒
Maurice Miller,
浑名叫史努比 以前是拳手
also known as snoopy, used to be a prizefighter.
我知道史努比 这人很难搞
I know snoopy. He's a fucking whack job.
他认为他是雷·伦纳德
You know, he thinks he's sugar ray Leonard.
在西部
Hangs out over on the West Side
和另外几个头号笨蛋一起
with a couple of other first-rate nut cases.
我要地址
I'm gonna need a last-known address.
2710 你要什么?
27-10 coming in. You're gonna need what?
最近的地址
A last known address.
那是你的车吗?
That your car?
我不喜欢你和米勒单独见面
No way. I don't want you talking to Miller alone.
得了 雷 我是联邦人员
Come on, ray. I'm a federal officer.
我有枪
I can handle myself. I'm armed.
明天我再打电话告诉你地址
I'll call you tomorrow with the address.
谢谢你 雷
Thank you, Raymond.
你看报纸了吗?
Buddy: You see the paper?
她很上镜头
Jack: It's a terrific shot of her.
除了这
Buddy: Outside of that.
我不认为她来此
Doesn't say what she's doing here,
跟我们有关系
but I don't think it has anything to do with us.
她是来渡假 因为这里狗屎天气
She came here on vacation because she likes shitty weather.
我想她是来抓葛兰的
I think she's after Glenn.
那女的在吗
The girl still there?
除非你给钱 否则她们不会留下过夜
Buddy: They don't stay the whole night, Jack, unless you pay for it.
你有没有告诉你姐姐?
Tell your sister about it?
有 我刚打了 她为我祈祷
Yeah, I just hung up. She prayed for me.
你打了多久?
Mm-hm. And how long were you on the phone with her?
两个小时
Two hours.
你跟那女的呢?
And how long were you with the girl?
四十五分钟
45 minutes.
你跟你姐姐谈到瑞利了吗?
You didn't tell your sister about Ripley, did you?
别再提我姐姐了
Look, Jack, just forget about my sister, okay?
如果凯伦盯著葛兰 我们就惨了
Now, if Karen sisco is tailing Glenn, we're fucked.
明晚我们都会被抓
Tomorrow night at the fights we all get picked up.
我们先去剧院 看看
Listen, why don't we just drive by where we're meeting tonight, check it out
再去瑞利家
and go by Ripley's too, while we're at it.
好吧
- Yeah, all right. - All right.
安瑟旅馆 我能否为你服务?
Female opera Tor: Athenaeum hotel, how may I help you?
请找凯伦西思柯
Karen sisco, please.
好西部旅馆
Opera Tor: Hello. Best western.
请找凯伦西思柯
Karen sisco, please.
莫塞米勒吗?
Moselle Miller?
你找谁?
What do you want?
我找莫瑞
I'm looking for Maurice.
你找到他 说他那只狗死了
You find him, tell him the dog got run over,
我没有伙食钱了
and I'm out of grocery money.
你在和谁说话?
Kenneth: Moselle, who you talkin' to?
有个女的找莫瑞
Lady lookin' for Maurice.
-她要什么 -她没说
- Kenneth: What does she want? - Moselle: Hasn't said.
那不是莫瑞?
That's not Maurice?
那是我弟弟肯尼
That's Kenneth, my brother. He's talking on the phone.
问她找他干什么
Kenneth: Ask her what she want with him!
你去问她！
You ask her!
莫瑞的事与我无关
Maurice business is none of my business.
你妈的对
Kenneth: You damn right.
剧场? 谁在比赛?
State theater, huh? Who's fightin'?
黑鬼 怎么样?
Nigga, what?
我在找一个莫瑞认识的人
Karen: I'm looking for somebody I think Maurice knows.
你不是缓刑小组来的吧?
You're not with probation, one of those?
-不是 -你是律师吗?
- No. - You a lawyer?
不是 我在找葛兰麦克
No, I'm not. I'm looking for somebody named Glenn Michaels.
我不认识什么葛兰
Glenn? I don't know any Glenn.
他说他去年11月待在这里
He said he stayed here last November.
在这房子里?
Here in this house?
他说他和莫瑞在一块
He said he stayed with Maurice.
连莫瑞都不常来了
Well, he ain't even here that much.
我想知道他到那去了
I'd like to know where he goes, but at the same time
又不想知道 你懂吗?
I don't wanna know, you understand?
我懂
你的狗死了?
You say your dog was killed?
被车碾死的了
Got run over by a car.
它叫什么?
What'd you call him?
它是母的 叫塔菲
It was a she. Named tuffy.
你想我在那里可以找到莫瑞?
Where do you think I might find Maurice, moselle?
我不知道 健身房?拳击场?
I don't know. The gym, the fights.
他从不错过拳赛
I know he don't miss the fights.
明天晚上剧场里有拳赛
Havin' some tomorrow night down at the state theater.
他以前都带我去
He used to take me.
剧场
The state theater.
你为什么问一大堆有关莫瑞的事?
Why you askin' all these questions about Maurice?
她在找一个叫葛兰的人
She lookin' for a man name of Glenn.
我问你了吗?办你的事去
Did I ask you? Go on and do something with yourself, moselle.
你去给我们拿点吃的来
Why don't you take your ass to doc nella's and get us some shrimp or something?
你打拳
You're a fighter.
你怎么知道？
How you know that?
我看得出来
I can tell.
我是
Yeah, I was.
直到我的视网膜剥落了二次
'Til I got my retina detached two times.
你打那一级?中量级?
What'd you fight, about middleweight?
轻量级
No. Light.
超中量级 等我长壮一点
Super middleweight, once my body developed.
你打那一级?羽量级?
What you go about, what, a bantam?
蝇量级
Flyweight.
黑鬼 怎样?该知道你的等级
Nigga, what? You know your divisions, huh?
你喜欢打拳吗?你喜欢动粗吗?
Did you like the fights? You like the rough stuff?
我想你一定喜欢
Yeah, I bet you do.
想不想下来干一场?
You like to get down and tussle a little bit?
像从前我和塔菲一样
Like me and tuffy, before... Before she got run over.
我们常在地上扭在一块
We used to get down on the floor and tussle all the time.
我告诉它“塔菲” 你这只好狗这个好吃的给你”
I'd say to her, "you a good bitch, tuffy. Here's a treat for ya."
我给塔菲所有母狗都爱的
I'd give tuffy what all good bitches love best,
你知道是什么吗?
and you know what that is?
知道那是什么吗?一块骨头
Know what that is? A bone.
我也会给你一块好的骨头
I'll give you a good bone too, girl.
你不是我喜欢的那种人
You're not my type.
那话对我没意义
That shit don't mean nothin' to me.
我掏出我的大家伙……
I let the monster out, you gonna do what it wants.
我得走了
I gotta go, Kenneth.
说不定我们会再见面
Maybe we'll see each other again.
不 我们先干一场
No, no, no, no, we gonna tussle first.
妈的！那是什么鬼东西?
Damn it! What the fuck was that?
你想干一场 我们来干
You wanted to tussle. We tussled.
那是个大房子
Buddy: That's a big ass house.
这地方就像监狱
Jack: Place almost looks like a prison.
他可真有一套 复杂的保安系统
Buddy: No doubt he's got some serious security system.
到时候 我们去敲门
Time comes, we go up, knock on the door,
看他要不要叙旧
see if he wants to talk about old times.
-太简单了 -酷
- Go in the easy way. - Cool.
有史努比和那一身肉的混蛋 他会让我们进去吗?
Think he'll let us in we got snoop and that musclebound asshole with us?
没有别人
Nobody's gonna be with us.
明晚我们去看拳赛 听听史努比的大计划
I saw we go to the fights tomorrow night, see what snoopy's big plan is,
然后我们比他快一步
then we go in ahead of him. Alone.
好主意
I can dig it.
当我们去逍遥的时候 让葛兰去应付史努
Let Glenn deal with the snoop, while we off iivin' the good life.
你知道有谁做了一大笔
Good life. Buddy, you know anybody who's done one last big score
然後就逍遥法外了?
and then gone on to live the good life?
我们也有可能空手而归
Look, Jack. There's a chance we'll walk out of here with nothin'.
我看 听天由命吧
I say, let fate decide.
命运?你是什么 他妈的达赖喇嘛?
Let fate decide? What are you, the fuckin' Dalai Lama now?
是我姊姊
Nah, man, it's my sister.
我姊姊相信命运不相信地狱
My sister believes in fate but not hell.
她不再为丧失灵魂的人祷告
That's why she stopped praying for all the lost souls,
虽然你不肯再听赎罪之类的话
since you don't hear that much about purgatory anymore.
但她每天仍为巴蒂祷告希望他不出事
But every day, she ask her boss to pray that buddy don't fuck up.
你认为呢?
I mean, what do you think?
你认为地狱存在吗?
- Do you think there's a hell? - Yeah.
葛雷兹监狱就是
It's called the glades correctional institute.
我决不回到像那样的地方去
I'm sure as shit not going back there, or any place like it.
他们用枪对著你 你就得去
They put a gun on you, you'll go, brother.
那怕有枪 你还是有选择的余地
They put a gun on you, you still have a choice.
所以 弗理先生
Man: So, Mr. Foley.
瑞利先生和我长谈过
Mr. Ripley and I have had along discussion
你在公司上班的事
about your role in the company
他觉得你在迈阿密上班会愉快些
and it was his feeling you'd be happiest working down here in Miami.
怎么样？
How's that sound to you?
好极了
Sounds great.
好 你穿42号加长的 对吗?
Good. You're about a 42 long, right?
我大概是穿42号
I'm about a 42.
像 42号普通的
Like, 42 regular.
穿穿看合不合身
Okay, let's see how she fits.
-这是什么? -你的制服
- What is that? - Your uniform.
我的制服?
My uniform.
弗理先生
Foley.
-弗理先生 -先生！ 请等等
- Mr. Foley. - Sir. Excuse me, sir.
先生！ 请等等
Sir. Sir, excuse me.
你不能进去！有警卫？
- Sir, you can't go in there! - You fucking kidding me?
你搞什么 昏了头啦? 嘿 别发火！
A security guard? What are you, stoned?
没关系
Hey, hey. Take it easy!
佩姬 没事了
It's all right, Peggy. It's under control.
听我说
You know something,
我不确定你会来 但我知道如果你来了
I wasn't sure that you'd show up here, but I was very sure if you did,
你也会把这差事扔到我脸上
you'd throw this job in my face.
让我告诉你吧
Let me tell you something.
到今天为止你所做的
Every single thing you've done with your life up until this point
都没有任何意义
in the real world means nothing.
一点意义也没有
Less than nothing.
你是个抢银行的
You're a bank robber.
那是个见不得人的本事
That's not a very marketable skill.
谁看过抢银行的
We don't see a lot of old bank robbers walking around
领养老金了?
with a pension plan, now do we?
我想你懂这个道理所以你才会来这里
I think you know this. That's why you're here.
今天 我给你……
Today, I've offered you
一个烂工作 烂薪水
a lousy job with a lousy wage.
你要好一点的工作?证明你能改头换面给我看
You want something better? Why don't you show me you can change.
我才会给你好点的差事
Then I'll offer you something better. A lot better.
在这之前 老兄 你得去赚
But until then, my friend, you'll have to earn it.
怎么赚 狄克?像你这样?
How, dick? The way you earn it?
讨个开公司的富婆
Married some rich broad owns the company,
卖了公司 再和她离婚?
selling it off a piece at a time then divorcing her?
说什么“自食其力”的狗屎?
Is this... this new rocky "pull yourself up by the bootstraps" bullshit?
在监狱里 像你这种人?
Back in prison, a guy like you in a place like that?
一定会被整得稀巴烂
You were ice cream for freaks. A goddamned dumpling.
莫瑞和其他的家伙会要你的命
Maurice and a dozen other guys
打死你
would have bled you till you had nothing.
是我救了你的狗命
Until you were nothing. I saved your ass!
抱歉我不愿坐椅子上
So you'll pardon me if I don't wanna sit on a fucking stool all day,
还要说“请签名”
and say, "sign in here, please,"
或“你不能停在这里”
or "hey, pal, you can't park here," all right, dick?
我不能干这种事 狄克
I can't fuckin' do it, dick!
你让我失望
I'm disappointed in you.
又来了
You know what?
他答应了你们这些人什么?
Oh. Here we go. What job did he promise you boys?
我们有二种办法
There's two ways we can do this.
什么办法?
Yeah, what are they?
山托斯银行
我必需买双好鞋以及明天用的东西
Hey buddy, I gotta get a better pair of shoes and some things for tomorrow.
我们一会儿见
Drop me off by the rents and we'll hook up later.
好
Yeah, okay.
我最好打个电话给我姊姊
I better go call my sister.
要喝点什么？
Waitress: Can I get you anything?
我要波本和水
May, I have a bourbon, please? Water back.
好
Okay.
你为什么不问我们还要什么?
Hey, Zach. Why don't you do us again, please?
席莱 那女士的酒算我们的
Celeste, put the lady's drink on our bill.
好的
Celeste: Okay.
他们要请你喝杯酒
They want to buy your drink for you.
我想也是
Yeah, I get that.
告诉他们我情愿自己付
Tell them I'd rather pay for my own.
好的
Okay.
我来问问看
I'll find out.
对不起 我和同事们打了个赌
Excuse me. My associates and I, we made a little bet
看看你是干哪一行的?
on what you do for a living.
我打赢了 我叫菲利普
And I won. Hi, I'm Philip.
菲利普 我只想安静的喝一杯酒走
If it's okay with you, Philip, I'd rather just have a quiet drink and leave.
难道你不想知道我是怎么知道的?
Don't you want to know what I guessed?
我怎么知道你是干什么的？
How I know what you do for a living?
我并不想对你不礼貌 我只是想清静一下
Really, Philip, I don't want to be rude. I just want to be left alone.
她有点冷淡
Philip: It's a little cold over there.
我知道你为什么这么沮丧
Excuse me. I think I know why you're depressed.
我能把我的意见告诉你吗?
If I can offer my observation.
我猜你是新来的推销员
See, I got a hunch you're the new sales rep,
你的客户并不十分满意 因为处理他们户头的
and the client's not exactly knocked out by the fact that a young lady,
竟然是一位像你这么年轻的小姐
even one as stunning as yourself, is handling the account.
我猜得很对吧?
Am I close?
我是安迪
I'm Andy.
我们都是广告业的 今天早上才从纽约飞来的
We're all ad guys. Flew in this morning from the apple. New York.
替“河边路人”酒厂做广告
Came in to pitch hiram Walker distillery.
给新的玛格丽特鸡尾酒做试售计划
Little test market campaign for the new Margarita mix.
那真的是很有意思 比方说
It's really pretty interesting. We take this...
麦克司…西裔的土匪
Mex... hispanic bandito
挂著子弹带 拿了家伙戴了一个大帽子
with his bullet belts and everything, and the big chihuahua hat,
然后他拔出六发子弹的枪
and he pulls out his six-guns.
我背后的那些家伙
And uh, these guys back here...
安迪
Andy.
谁管这些狗屎?
Really. Who gives a shit?
要不要告诉我怎么回事儿?
Do you want to tell me what happened?
滚开 安迪
Beat it, Andy.
安迪
Andy.
你做了什么?
What'd you do?
我能请你喝杯酒吗？
Can I buy you a drink?
好 来一杯
Yeah, I'd love one.
坐下
Sit down.
我是盖瑞
I'm Gary.
我是席莱
I'm Celeste.
只有一个女侍
It takes forever to get a drink here.
我可以到吧台去
- There's only one waitress. - I can go to the bar.
别去
No. Don't go.
他们烦你了？
Are those guys bothering you?
没事 你刚到吗?
They're fine. I mean, you just got here.
来 喝一点
Here, help yourself.
你喜欢波本酒?
You like bourbon?
我喜欢
I love it.
席莱 告诉我 你是干哪一行的?
We got that outta the way. Tell me, Celeste, what do you do for a living?
我是个推销员 来拜访一位客户
I'm a sales rep, and I came here to call on a customer,
因为我是女的 他们就刁难我
but they gave me a hard time 'cause I'm a girl.
你是这么想你自己的吗?
Is that how you think of yourself?
推销员？女人
- As a sales rep? - As a girl.
我无所谓
I don't have a problem with it.
我喜欢你的发型
I like your hair.
我喜欢你的打扮
I like your outfit.
这是我第二喜欢的一套衣服
Actually this is my second favorite outfit.
我最喜欢的一套已经被糟蹋了只好扔了
I had a first favorite, but it got ruined, and I had to get rid of it.
-真的？ -臭臭的
- You did? - It smelled.
洗了也没用  对
Really? Having it cleaned didn't help?
盖瑞 你做什么的?
So tell me, Gary, what do you do for a living?
你还要这样继续多久?
How far do you want to go with this?
先别说甚么
Not yet. Don't say anything yet.
没用的 我们就是我们
I don't think it works if we're somebody else.
盖瑞和席莱 他们知道甚么?
Gary and Celeste, what do they know about anything?
我没玩过这种游戏
Well, this is your game, I've never played before.
这不是游戏
It's not a game.
不是你玩的游戏
It's not something you play.
对你有意义吗?
Does this make any sense to you?
不须要有意义 是自然发生的
It doesn't have to. It's something that happens.
像在街上第一次看到一个人
It's like seeing someone for the first time
你以为你们会擦肩而过
like you could be passing on the street,
你们彼此看了几秒……
and you look at each other and for a few seconds
就觉得你们彼此灵犀相通
there's this kind of a recognition... Like you both know something.
但下一刻 那人就走了
The next moment, the person's gone,
也来不及做甚么
and it's too late to do anything about it.
你会永远记得 你错过了某些东西
You always remember it, because it was there, and you let it go.
你告诉自己 “假如我停下来了呢?”
You think to yourself, "what if I had stopped? What if I had said something?
“假如……”
What if?
这种事一生中只会发生几次
And it may only happen a few times in your life.
或一次
Or once.
你怎么找到我的?
Karen: How'd you find me?
啊恩 我在楼下打到你的房间
I called your room from downstairs.
哦 如果我接电话 你要说甚么?
And I if I had answered, what were you gonna say?
说我是谁 你记得我吗?
Jack: I would say who I was, and do you remember me,
要不要一起喝一杯？
and if you'd want to meet for a drink?
记得你吗？我来这儿就为找你
Karen: Ifl remembered you? I came here looking for you.
然后我会说好 但你知道
All right, so then I would have said yes, but for all you know,
我也可能让霹雳小组等著你 你为什么信任我?
I could have had a SWAT team waiting for you. Why would you trust me?
值得冒险
Jack: It'd be worth the risk.
-你喜欢冒险 -你也是
- Karen: You like taking risks. - Jack: So do you.
迟早……
Karen: You know, sooner or later...
你真的穿那套套装
You really wear that suit.
这不是你想说的
That's not what you were about to say.
你记得你在后车厢里多爱讲话?
Remember how talkative you were in the trunk?
阿黛儿说你一紧张就爱讲话
Adele said you do that when you're nervous.
她这么说吗?
She did, did she?
你一直摸我的大腿
Karen: You kept touching me, feeling my thigh.
但我没恶意
Jack: But in a nice way.
你拿走的西格枪有特殊意义
You know, that sig that you took from me was special.
是我爸送我的生日礼物
My dad gave it to me for my birthday.
是吗?
Yeah?
你要把我怎么办?
What were you going to do with me?
我还没想出来
Jack: I hadn't really worked that part out yet.
我只知道我喜欢你 不想……
All I knew was that I liked you, and didn't want to
离开你就再也见不到你了
leave you there on the side of the road and never see you again.
你在电梯里招手
Karen: Then you waved to me in that elevator.
我以为你没看到我
Jack: I wasn't sure you caught that.
我无法相信 我一直…
Karen: I couldn't believe it. By that time, I had been...
很想你
Thinking about you a lot
而且一直想如果我们再见面
andjust wondering what it would be like if we met,
如果我们能让时间停止
if we could take a time-out.
我也这么想
I was... I was thinking the same thing.
如果我们能让时间停止
I kept thinking, "what if we took a time-out?"
如果我们能在一起一段时间
If we... 'Cause... just spent some time together.
-我在街上看到过你 -哪里？
- Jack: You know, I saw you on the street. - Karen: Where?
阿黛儿家外面
Jack: Outside Adele 's.
你去看她?
Karen: You went to see her?
去警告她要小心奇诺
Jack: To warn her about chino.
她帮了你?
Karen: So she did help you.
我们不该谈这些
Jack: I don't think we should get into that.
对 我也不会问巴蒂的事
Karen: You're right. And I won't ask about buddy, or
或你是否见到了葛兰
what you guys are doing in Detroit, or if you've run into Glenn Michaels yet...
别这么说 你让我害怕
Jack: Okay, now, don't talk like that, because you scare me.
我们走吧
Let's get out of here.
好的
Yeah.
有些事情我要你知道
There's something I want you to know.
我并不是在找乐子
I wasn't just looking for a fuck,
如果你是这么想的话
if that's what you're thinking.
怎么了?
- Or I was a... - Why are you mad?
我不是在寻刺激 和一个抢银行的
I was looking for some kinky thrill, you know, score with the bank robber.
像有些女人喜欢粗暴的……对
- The way some women go for rough... - All right.
我不会说我干了一个联邦女警 你想我会吗?
Now I can say that I fucked a U.S. marshal. Do you think I will?
我不知道
I don't know.
Mm-hm.
过来
Come here.
我认识一个家伙……
I know a guy,
带了个瓶子进了银行 说那是硝化甘油
walks into a bank with a bottle, tells everybody it's nitroglycerine.
他从柜台搞了些钱
He scores some cash off of the teller.
走出银行时 瓶子掉到地上
On his way out, he drops the bottle. It cracks on the floor.
他滑倒跌破了头 被逮了
He slips in it. He smacks up his head. They get him.
那油只是沙拉油
The nitroglycerine was canola oil.
抢银行的笨贼
I know more fucked-up bank robbers
总比高明的要多
than ones that know what they're doing.
我怀疑有几个抢银行的知道什么是染色袋
I doubt one in ten could tell you what a dye pack is.
大部份抢银行的都是蠢蛋
Most bank robbers are fucking morons.
让你到床上找刺激的蠢蛋
For you to go to bed with one for kinky thrills,
像你说的 你也变得和他们一样蠢
like you were saying, makes you as dumb as they are.
事实上 你不蠢
Now, you are not dumb.
你怎么会那么想?你怎么认为我会那么想?
Why would you think that? Why would you think that I would think that?
你不蠢
You're not dumb.
我不晓得
Well, I don't know about that.
你不能跌了三跤后还认为自己不笨
You can't do three falls and think you have much of a brain.
过来
Come here.
你现在对我认真了
You're getting serious on me now.
我尽量不想
Tryin' not to.
我只是想知道会发生什么
I just want to know what's gonna happen.
你知道的
You know.
周五夜拳赛
防守 打他上面 下面
Put it together now. Put it together. Upstairs, not downstairs.
他不想在楼下见到你
He don't want to see you downstairs!
你醉得像婊子
Man, you drink like a bitch!
别下去 准备打吧
He don't wanna see you... Get your tussle on! Get your tussle on!
别让他离开那个角落
Yeah, don't let him out that corner.
别让他出去
Don't let him out, now.
我要去小便
Hey, you know what? I gotta go take a pee.
告诉我们干什么?要我们替你扶老二啊
What are you tellin' us for? You want somebody to hold your pecker?
干下去 乔
Maurice: Do that work, Joe!
鼓起精神 乔
Put it together now, Joe!
对了
That's it, baby!
扁他 好极了
Take him deep! Oh, my god! I love it.
把他打昏 乔  把他打昏 乔
Put him to sleep, Joe! Put him to sleep, Joe!
坐下 肯尼 对了
Sit down, Kenny. That's it! That's it!
想偷这部车呀
Karen: Tryin' to steal this car, Glenn?
不要！
Don't! Don't, don't!
我不相信
Oh, my god, I can't believe this!
又倒霉了 没一件事情搞对
Another one of those days, huh? Nothing seems to be going right.
-我没有钥匙 -我知道
- I don't have the keys to the car. - I see that.
我不是要偷这辆车
No, I mean I am not fucking stealing the car!
你不是吗?
You're not?
不是 一周前已经偷到手了
No, I already stole it a week ago,
在西棕榈
whenever it was, in west palm.
我不可能再偷一次吧
So I can't be stealing it again, can I?
把手放在方向盘上  你要…
Put your hands on the wheel, please.
因为偷车逮捕我?
Oh, okay, so now you're gonna bust me for pickin' up a car?
为车 为协助犯人逃狱
For the car, for aiding and abetting a prison escape,
还为你到这里搞的不管什么名堂
and for conspiring to do whatever you came here for.
那些家伙随时都会出来找我
Listen to me, these guys, they're gonna be out here any minute looking for me,
他们是禽兽
and they're fucking animals, man.
发生什么事 葛兰?
What's going on, Glenn?
没事 我只是想离开这鬼地方
Nothing. I just wanna get the fuck outta here.
我还以为这件事是你的主意
I thought this whole thing was your idea.
打劫瑞利家是我的主意
Okay, ripping off Ripley was my idea,
但这些家伙另有搞法
but these guys, they are in a whole other level of their own.
瑞利 那个华尔街的家伙?
Ripley, the wall street guy?
计划是明天到他办公室接他
Yeah. The plan was to pick him up at his office tomorrow
搭他到布伦坡他家
and drive him out to his house in bloomfield hills.
现在 我不跟那鸟人做 你知道！
And now I don't give a shit what the guys do, you know.
弗理有份吗?
And foley was part of this?
有 但他还没出现
Yeah, he's supposed to be, but he hasn't showed up yet,
那倒对他好  为什么?
- which is good for him. - Why?
莫瑞要干掉他……
Because Maurice is gonna kill him
想拿赏金甚么的
to like, try to collect the reward money or something.
但你说他还没现身 他是打退堂鼓了吗?
But you say he hasn't shown up yet. You think he backed out?
我不知道 他不会告诉我这些
I don't know. He doesn't exactly confide in me.
奇怪
I wonder why.
你如果想做 我们做了就离开这里
Okay, now, if you're gonna do this, let's do it and get out of here.
我的屁股冻坏了
I am freezing my ass off!
你想溜 就跑吧 这样会暖和些
If you wanna get out of here, run. It'll warm you up.
哦！哦！
Oh, ha, ha.
真的？
Really?
如果我发现你在骗我 我发誓……
I swear to god, Glenn, if I find out that you are lying to me...
我知道 你会找到我的
I know, you will find me. I believe it.
知道我在想什么吗?
Hey, you know what I was thinking?
去年夏天如果你没载我到联邦法院
If you didn't drive me to the federal court last summer,
你就不认识我了
you wouldn't even know who I am.
如果我不认识你 葛兰 明天你不是坐牢就是死了
If I didn't know you, Glenn, by tomorrow you'd be in jail or dead.
要那样去想 现在跑吧
Think of it that way. Now run.
耶！ 耶！
我告诉你吧 钱在这里
I'm tellin' you, man, the money is here.
史努
Snoop.
抢银行的
Hey, it's the bank robbers, man.
我会错过拳赛 抓把椅子来
Y'all missin' the fights, man. Pull up a chair.
谁坐在那里
Who's sittin' here?
葛兰
Oh, that's your homie, Glenn, man,
他去上厕所了……
but he bounced to the bathroom a couple of minutes ago,
之后我们就没见过他
and we ain't seen him since.
一定是掉到茅坑里了
Must've fell in, man.
没错
No doubt.
叫那两个人去找他
Yeah, sent these two looking for him, man.
他们没找到
They came back shaking their heads.
如果他留下外套 又离开了一阵子……
Well, if he left his coat and he's been gone a while, then...
车还在 我查过了
Car's here, man. I checked.
我们走了
All right, we're ieavin'.
走了?
Leavin'?
干嘛? 如果葛兰跑了…
- What the fuck? - Snoop, if you know where Glenn is...
谁在乎 他什么也不知道
Look, man, what you worried about Glenn for, man? What he know?
我以为他全知道
I thought everything.
葛兰以为我们明天才要干
No, Glenn know everything that's supposed to happen tomorrow.
就算他跑了把我们的事告诉别人 也无关紧要
He may run and tell somebody that, but that don't mean shit, you understand?
葛兰不知道我改变了计划
Glenn don't know I changed the plan.
今天晚上一离开这里我们就行动
It's happenin' tonight. Soon as we leave here.
绕到我家 拿些我们需要的家伙
Go back by the house, pick up some shit we gonna need,
就这么干！
and we just go do it.
给我几分钟跟巴蒂商量
Give me a minute to talk to buddy.
最多给你两分钟
You got two minutes. That's all.
你作决定
Make up your mind, foley.
我不是要你批准
I wasn't asking permission.
他们会对我们下圈套
You know they're gonna set us up.
我有同感
I get that feeling, yeah.
你想我们可以在他们之前找到钻石吗?
You think you can get to the diamonds before they do?
跟你谈个交易 你现在就离开这里
I'll make you a deal. You get outta here right now.
我和史努一起做
I'll do the job with snoop,
再和你见面分你一半
I'll meet you anywhere you want, give you half.
为什么分我一半?
Half for doin' what?
因你帮我逃狱
Gettin' me out of glades, for starters.
谁会在背后照应你?
Who's gonna watch your back?
好了 白鬼 家庭访间
All right, white boy. House call.
耶 耶 耶
准备好了?
Ready to do this, baby?
好了
Ready for whatever.
正点！我这一套每次都管用
Cool. My shit always work.
长生水电
White boy: Perennial plumbing.
有人打电话给我们
Somebody in the house called.
你搞错了 没人在家
You don't know what you're talking about, because no one was here.
我们去滑雪  耶 耶 耶
- Let's go skiing. - Kenneth: Yeah.
你仍可以接受我的条件
Jack: You still got time to take me up on my offer.
留你和这些蠢蛋在一起?
Buddy: And leave you alone with these assholes?
雷门库兹
Raymond Cruz.
我是凯伦 我在瑞利家
Ray, it's Karen sisco. I'm at Ripley's house.
莫瑞米勒和另外四个人刚闯进去
I just saw Maurice Miller and four other suspects force their way into the house.
我需要后援
They're armed. I'm gonna need backup.
你是谁? 我在这里工作
- Maurice: Who are you? - Midge: I work here.
我是女佣 别过来
I'm the maid. Fuck off!
我偏要这么做 先干你 再扁你
That's exactly what I'm gonna do, fuck you, then off you.
Hey, hey, hey, not yet, not yet.
端利在哪里?
Where Ripley at?
他不在这里
He isn't here.
晚上出去还是搞什么?
Out for the evening or some shit?
他在佛罗里达
He's in Florida, palm beach.
什么时候回来?
When's he due back?
你们要等他啊
What difference does it make? You gonna wait for him?
瑞利先生整个季节都在那里 从圣诞到复活节
Mr. Ripley's down for the season. Christmas to easter.
少放屁
Stop that shit, man.
你一个人在这里?
You're here all by yourself?
是的 只有我
That's right. Just me.
瑞利的保险箱和贵重品在哪?
Where Ripley's safe at, keeps his valuables in?
我不知道
I don't have any idea.
我谅你也不知道
Ifuckin' bet you don't.
我们要上楼到他的卧室找一找
We gonna take a look upstairs in the man's bedroom, all right?
你和巴蒂找楼下的房间
You and Mr. Buddy look at all the rooms down here.
检查那些画 以及墙后
Check the paintings, behind the walls. Check the fuckin' walls in the closets.
他一定有保险箱 在这附近
The man's got a safe, okay? It's here somewhere.
会不会在他佛罗里达的家里?
What about his place down in Florida?
如果你先查明 我们在佛罗里达时
If you'd called, we could have checked
就先查那些墙了
the walls down there before we left.
我是说如果你愿找到他的话
That is, if you'd bothered to find out where he was, you follow me?
把这婊子带上楼
Man, take this bitch upstairs.
上楼
Upstairs!
Mm-mm-mm-m-mm-mm.
你如果想按警铃 或甚么的话
Listen. You try and trip any alarms, anything like that,
你就死定了 明白吗?
you gonna be a dead Hazel, you understand me?
我们在哪里?保险箱在哪里?
Hey, hey, hey, hey. Where we at? Where is it?
那里
Over there.
穿过这个吗?
Ever wear one of these?
我不滑雪
I don't ski.
看好那个女佣 我要到处看看
Keep an eye on the maid. I'll have a look around.
坐下来
Go sit down. Please.
妈的 这痞子过这种生活
Damn, mo. How's this motherfucker iivin', man?
靠
Shit!
检查墙上画的后面
Check behind the pictures on the walls, man.
喂 找到一些套子
Hey, mo. Found some rubbers.
白波 你为什么在床垫下找?
White boy, why the fuck you iookin' under the mattress?
那家伙不会把钻石藏在那儿的
You know dude ain't gonna hide no diamonds under there.
妈的 这个痞子
Damn! Dumb 'bama motherfucker.
弗理在哪里?
Where foley at, man?
照你说的 在检查别的房间
He's checkin' the other rooms like you said, boss.
盯好他
Man, keep an eye on foley.
肯 别动那收音机 放张CD
Maurice: Ken, stop fuckin' with the radio, man, put on a cd.
这些乐队我一个都不认识
I don't recognize none of these bands, mo.
随便找一个
Just pick somebody.
什么 “如何唱的像麦克波顿”
What, "how to sing like Michael Bolton"?
你想听什么?
What the fuck you wanna listen to, huh?
我喜欢舒伯特
I like schubert.
舒伯特 我不喜欢
Schubert? Well, I don't.
弗理！
Uh, foley?
酷
Cool.
911占线啊 理查
9-1-1 got you on hold, Richard?
-弗理！-还好吗？
- Foley! - How you doin'?
到底发生什么事?
What in god's name is happening here?
谁在楼上?
Who's upstairs?
史努比米勒 几个他的朋友
Snoopy Miller, couple of his friends.
莫瑞 兰坡监狱的那个?
- Maurice, from lompoc? - Yup.
他们把美姬抓住了吗
Have they got midge up there?
有哪个男人那么晚让女人应门?
What kind of a man lets a woman answer the door this time of night?
我们以为那是她丈夫来这里查看她
We thought it was her husband. He comes here and checks up on her.
我应该在佛罗里达的
I'm supposed to be down in Florida.
待会儿你就会巴不得自己是在佛罗里达了
In a few minutes, you're gonna wish you were. Let's go. Come on.
坐下 看鱼吧
Sit down. Have a look at your fish.
这个行 这个行
That's workin'. That's workin'. Yeah.
干你娘 我找到保险箱了
Motherfucker! I found the safe, yo!
哪儿都别去
Don't go nowhere.
妈的 我们要庆祝一下  瞧那婊子
- Oh, shit! We gonna have a party! - Look at that bitch.
找到保险箱了
They found the safe.
干
Fuck.
巴蒂 你记得理查吗?
Buddy, you remember Richard, don't you?
嘿 房子不错
Yeah, hi. Nice house.
谢谢
Thank you.
我们可以敲这个把手
Yeah, man, we just all hit this handle,
把这炸开
blow this sucker wide open, man.
准备一下
Yeah, yeah. Let's get ready.
你想用这玩意儿干掉我
Oh! Dude, you're gonna kill me with that.
你去哪儿了?
Where you been, man?
找到一些牛排
Found some steaks.
牛排
Steaks?
好大一块
Some big ones, bro.
来吧 把这保险箱炸开
Man, come on, blast this damn safe open.
他在那儿找吃的
He's down there lookin' for food.
蠢蛋
Fool.
拿好 不对 到一边去
All right. Hold it. No. Get to the side, man.
好了
All right.
数到三 一、二、三
On three. One, two, three.
老天 他们在对美姬开枪
Jesus Christ, they're shooting midge!
坐下 迪克 他们在打开保险箱 不是你的女佣
Sit down, dick. They're trying to open up the safe, not your maid.
妈的
Kenneth: Oh, shit.
连个破洞也没有
We didn't even crack this son of a bitch.
打那门铰链
Okay. Hit the hinges.
捂住你的耳朵 这声音会很响
Put your finger in your ear, man. This is gonna be loud.
数到三  一、二……
All right, on three. One, two...
暗码是31044
The combination is 3-10-44.
理查的生日
Richard's birthday.
多谢
Thank you.
他们挂了?
Are they dead?
我们得找弗理
We gotta find foley, man.
真不敢相信事过境迁你还生我气
Can't believe you're still angry with me after all this time.
我没生你的气 老实说 我真看开了
I'm not angry with you, Richard. In fact, I'm completely relaxed.
我真搞不懂 是鱼让我冷静下来
The thing is, I can't figure if it's the fish that are cooling me out,
还是水箱底下那些未切割的钻石
or all those uncut diamonds in the bottom of the tank, there.
该死
Goddamn.
葛兰说得没错 那大概值五百万吧?
Dumb-fuck Glenn was right. You got about five million-worth in there?
五百二十万
Five point two.
看起来就像不起眼的石头
They just look like plain ol' rocks!
对 你想抓一把吗?
They sure do. You wanna grab 'em, buddy?
如果换了我是你 我拔腿就溜了
If I were you, I'd get up and run.
我不能留下美姬
I'm not leaving midge.
他们会杀了你
Don't be an asshole, they're gonna kill you.
那我就认命了
Well, if that's my fate then so be it.
我不离开她 我爱上她了
But I'm not leaving her. I'm in love with her.
算了 杰克
Come on, Jack.
祝你好运 理查
Good luck, Richard.
快点 杰克
Come on, Jack.
-该死 -怎么了？
- Shit. - What?
他们要强暴那个女佣 是吗
They're gonna rape that maid, aren't they?
看样子是
By the look of those guys, the ripper too.
-然后再把他们干掉 -大概是吧
- Then they're gonna kill 'em. - At least.
Rip, rip.
狗娘养的
Tricky motherfucker.
那些是我的衣服吗
Are those my suits?
是我的 看看你
No. These are my suits. Look at you, man.
你都躲在哪儿了?
Where you been hidin', dick?
我们成了
We made it, didn't we?
先上车
All you gotta do is get in the Van, baby.
我要回去
I'm goin' back in.
我和你一起去
I'm goin' with you.
在机场和我碰头
No, you dump the Van, meet me at the airport.
我开瑞利的车来  杰克
I'll get one of Ripley's cars.
你和你老姊
-Jackn - buddy, listen,
大概会在电话里聊这事
the shit that's about to go down here,
聊上一个月
you'll be on the phone with your sister for a month.
我们现在扯平了
All I'm sayin' is we're square.
这儿
Here.
耶
Yup.
杰克
Jack.
滚开
Get out of here!
把这玩意拿下来
Kenneth: Get that shit off.
滚开
Midge: Get your hands off me!
闭嘴！没人会来救你
Kenneth: Fuck you! Shut up! Nobody's gonna help you.
不要！
Midge: No!
美姬
- Midge! - Fuck midge, man.
珠宝究竟在哪里?
Where the jewels at, dick?
弗理拿去了
Foley, foley's got them. Go after foley.
弗理在哪里?
Where the fuck is foley, man?
美姬
Midge.
美姬！
Midge!
给我坐下
Maurice: Sit your punk ass down, man.
猪猡
Son of a bitch!
你走前门 我走后门
Take the front stairs. I'm gonna take the back.
你没事吧？
You all right?
理查德在哪里？
Where's Richard?
在楼下 在这儿等著
He's downstairs. You wait here.
不许动 把枪丢下
Hold it, asshole. Drop the gun.
丢下
Drop it!
把枪放下 马上
Put the damn gun down, now.
放下
Put it down!
在那儿待著别动 莫瑞
Stay right there. Don't move. Maurice!
我找到弗理了
I got foley!
莫瑞
Maurice!
没有多的弹夹可给我用的?
You ain't got another clip I can use, do you?
没有
No, I don't.
从没开过枪吧?
You ain't never shot a gun before, have you?
对 最近才学会
Not until recently, no.
-有点紧张 -一点点
- You a little nervous? - Little bit, yeah.
在这种情况下 很可能
You know, uh, a situation like this has a high potentiality
被这些狗娘养的给逃了
for the common motherfucker to bitch out.
所以我想 为什么要冒险?
So I figure, why take a chance?
婊子
Bitch!
干你娘
Motherfucker!
住手 举起手来
Stop! Put your hands in the air!
杰克?
Karen: Jack!
我知道你在上面
I know you're up there.
呸
Shit!
肯尼在哪里
Karen: Where's Kenneth?
他在上面
He's up here.
他死了
He's dead.
算了 杰克 别这样
Come on, Jack, don't.
就当不是我
Pretend it's not me.
你以为我会对你开枪?
You think I'd shoot you?
你不开 别人也会开
If you don't, somebody else will.
你现在算什么?亡命之徒?
What're you now? A desperado?
把枪放下
Put the gun down.
我不回去坐牢
I'm not goin' back.
不要逼我 把枪放下
Jack, please, don't make me do this. Put the gun down.
浑蛋 杰克 把枪放下
Damn it, Jack, put the gun down!
没有时间了
No more time-outs.
算你赢 杰克
You win, Jack.
我没法射你
I can't shoot you.
你开枪了 你射中我
You did. You shot me.
你知道我的
You know what I mean.
抱歉 我真希望事情不这样
I'm sorry. I wish things were different.
机场
Airport.
他们还没确定是否要控他杀人罪
Karen: Yeah, they don't know yet if they want to bring him up on the homicides.
我想不会 他们会把他在关一阵子
I doubt if they will. The bureau's put a detainer on him.
等审完以后 他会回佛罗里达
So when they're through with him here, he'll go back to Florida.
你会把他押解回来吗?
Marshall: Are you gonna go get him?
可能 干嘛
Karen: It's possible. Why?
想想而已
Marshall: Well, you know, I was just thinking.
你可以一路上和他逍遥
You can have a nice time with him on the ride down,
续上你们之间的那段插曲
like picking up where your "interlude" or whatever it is that you call it left off,
然后把他扔回监狱
and then you can throw him in the shithouse.
他知道自己在做什么
Karen: He knew what he was doing.
没人逼他抢银行
Nobody forced him to Rob banks.
我可怜的女儿 真坚强
Marshall: My little girl. The tough babe.
我稍后再和你连络
Karen: I'll call you later.
再见
Marshall: Good-bye.
杰克
Karen: Jack.
给你一个礼物
I got you a present.
路上用的
Something for the road.
不过 旅途结束后
I'm gonna have to take it away, though,
我还是要收回的
soon as the ride is over.
杰克弗理?来见海极亨利
Officer: Jack foley? Meet hejira Henry.
这个名字很特别
What kind of a name is hejira?
是回教名字/NIt's islamic.
代表什么?
What's it stand for?
“海极”是西元622年墨罕默得逃离麦加意思
The "hejira" was Muhammad's flight from mecca in 622.
他的逃离?
His flight?
利文沃的兄弟给我取的名字
Brothers in leavenworth gave me that name.
你在和利文沃待过?
You were in leavenworth, huh?
-待过一段日子 -什么意思?
- For a time. - Meaning?
时间到我就走了
Meaning, the time came, I left.
你逃跑了
You busted out.
是从自己不愿待的地方离开
I prefer to think of it as an exodus from an undesirable place.
过多久你又被逮到?
How long before they caught up with you?
那一次吗?
That time?
还有多少次啊?
There were others?
那是第九次
Yeah. That was the ninth.
第九次?
The ninth?
如果把那次从监狱医院逃走也算的话 就是第十次
Well, ten if you count that prison hospital in Ohio I walked away from.
亨利 你倒跷头不少次
You done a lot of walkin', Henry.
海极
Hejira.
我们现在出发去葛雷兹
Hejira. Now we're off to glades.
好像是吧
Yeah, it looks that way.
我昨天晚上本来应该跟一个女警官走的
I was supposed to leave last night with the lady marshal but
不知为什么她要等
for some reason she wanted to wait.
是吗?
Jack: She did, huh?
我想两人坐车省点钱吧
Hejira: Guess it's cheaper taking two of us down in one Van.
可能 说不定她以为我们有很多可聊的
Could be. Maybe she thought we had a lot to talk about.
是吗?聊什么?
Really? Like what?
我不知道 到佛罗里达有好一段路要走
I don't know. Long ride to Florida.